Bonus Short Stories

The Season of Dancing Flowers

On a day not long after Rio first visited the village...

It was springtime, and cherry blossoms were in full bloom. When the gentle wind blew through, the cherry blossom petals would flutter and dance in the air. As the sun made its way across the sky, work began to slow down. Rio was walking around the village, led by Ruri and Sayo.

“Come on, Rio. It’s over here.”

Ruri’s arm was entangled with Rio’s as she pulled him insistently.

“I don’t mind following you, but could you tell me where we’re going, Ruri?” Rio said to Ruri’s back.

To be honest, Rio had no idea where they were heading. He had just finished his work and stepped out into the garden to train when the two appeared and whisked him away, just like that.

“Ahaha. I wanted to introduce you to some work friends of ours. Everyone’s actually gathered already, and they’re all really curious about you, Rio. Isn’t that right, Sayo?”

“Yes. Everyone was asking us questions during work today, too. About you. They all said they wanted to meet you, so...” Sayo said hesitantly.

“That’s right. Everyone’s so persistent, saying they want to see Rio. Since it’d be a huge mess if they all came to the house at once, we decided to bring you to them instead.”

“I see, so that’s what this is all about. In that case, please lead me there.”

Rio was very grateful for their actions, since he wanted to familiarize himself with the village as quickly as possible.

“Leave it to me. Now, let’s go! Leading one customer to their seat!” Ruri laughed happily and pulled Rio’s arm.

A smile tugged at Rio’s lips as he started walking. However, when he turned to look behind him, he saw Sayo standing there as still as a rock.

“Sayo?”

“...What’s wrong, Sayo?”

Sayo snapped back to her senses with a gasp when the other two addressed her. “N-No, it’s nothing. I was just thinking about how you two looked close...”

Ruri cocked her head in thought before calling Sayo closer to share her brilliant idea. “Really? Hmm... Ah, then you can come over here, too, Sayo!”

“O-Okay.” Despite her confusion, Sayo hurried over.

“Okay Sayo, you’re on my other side.” Ruri said.

“Huh...?”

“You’re going to help me guide Rio around from my other side, okay? Then the three of us will be close.” Ruri pulled Rio’s arm closer as she spoke to a shocked Sayo. She seemed to be telling Sayo to do the same as her.

“Haha...” Rio grinned bashfully. It didn’t seem right to resist, so he gave in.

“Eh, ah, umm...” Sayo blushed and looked between her arm and Rio’s.

“Come on, everyone’s waiting! Hurry it up!” Ruri said, spurred Sayo into movement.

Rio forced down his embarrassment and tried offering his arm to Sayo. “...Erm, please look after me, Sayo.” If he showed any embarrassment here, the mood would become unbearable.

“O-Okay. Then... Excuse me.”

Sayo nodded hesitantly and quietly slipped her arm around Rio’s. She seemed a bit nervous as she stared up unblinkingly. The three of them lined up together, and Rio smiled with a shy but peaceful smile.

“All right, now let’s head out for real. Let’s go!” Ruri nodded in satisfaction and walked them down the path between the rice fields in the direction they had to travel in.

Suddenly, a gust of wind blew around them, and the scenery around them became dyed a pale pink color

Way Home

In the village chief’s house, less than one month after Rio started living with Yuba and the others. Rio, Yuba, and Sayo were doing a bit of handiwork together. Suddenly, the front door opened, and Ruri energetically burst in.

“I’m home! Whoa, huh? Sayo hasn’t gone home yet? Everyone’s already wrapped up and gone home.” Once she stepped onto the clay floor, Ruri spotted Sayo in the living room and widened her eyes.

“Oh, is it that time already? We were completely focused on our work.” Yuba paused in her work and looked at the outside scenery through the open front door.

Rio stopped his work and directed his gaze outside the front door too. “It’s gotten a lot darker.”

“Sayo, you should head home soon. Rio, will you walk her back?” Yuba requested.

“Sure, I got it,” Rio agreed immediately. “Shall we go, Sayo?”

“I-It’s fine. I can get back by myself. I don’t want to trouble Sir Rio like that!” Sayo’s cheeks flushed with embarrassment as she rejected Rio’s offer.

“Sayo gets scared easily, so you have to walk her back. It’s already dark, so there won’t be many people walking around the village either, you know?”

“That’s right — there’s no need to be so reserved. Just have Rio walk you.”

Ruri and Yuba shook their heads in unison.

“Are... Are you sure?” Sayo looked at Rio inquisitively.

“I don’t mind,” Rio said lightly, putting on his shoes to go outside.

“O... Okay. Then, if you would please.” Sayo nodded excitedly and followed after Rio in a fluster.

“Rio, just because Sayo’s cute doesn’t mean you can make a pass at her when you’re alone!” Ruri said with a wicked grin.

“Huh...?”

“I would never.”

Rio denied Ruri’s words with a sidelong glance at Sayo, along with a bitter smile.

Ruri laughed flatly. “Ahaha, I’m just kidding. Go on, then. Look after Sayo,” she said, leaving it to Rio.

“Yes, let us go... Sayo?” Rio nodded and looked at her.

Sayo had frozen on the spot, however, and was staring at Rio in a daze. When Rio called her name, she flinched with a gasp.

“Ah... Y-Yes! P-Please be gentle with me! I’ll be in your care!” She bowed her head vigorously.

Rio’s eyes widened until they bulged.

“Ahaha, why would he have to be gentle if he’s just walking you home... What do you mean, Sayo?” Ruri laughed in amusement after a moment of silence, holding back her giggles.

“Huh...? Ah... N-No, that’s not it!! I-I didn’t mean it in a weird way!” Sayo denied with a great flurry of gestures.

“I see, I see. A weird way, huh? I wonder what way that is?” Ruri turned an inquisitive eye onto Sayo.

“N-Nothing...” Sayo replied, turning bright red and ducking her head.

“Come on, now. If you’re going to fool about, then do it outside. It’s getting later and later.”

Yuba, who had been watching their exchange pleasantly, offered a lifeline to the gradually shrinking Sayo.

“Okaaay. See you later, you two. Rio, Sayo’s afraid of the dark, so make sure you stick to the village roads!”

“I understand. Let’s really get going, now, Sayo.” With a faintly strained smile, Rio invited Sayo along, who remained frozen near the doorway outside.

“Yes,” she said.

“Are you afraid of the dark, Sayo?” Rio asked Sayo after they left the house and started down the road.

“...Eh, ah, umm... I’m not afraid, I’m just easily scared. When I’m alone, it’s kind of... I even get scared by the wind blowing the grass... J-Just like a child, right?” Sayo said with an embarrassed grin.

“No, I’m sure there are adults out there who don’t like that, either.”

“...Thank you very much. I’m really glad that you’re walking me home after all. It seems like everyone’s gone home already, so if I were alone now, I would have gotten scared and ran the whole way back.”

“Even the village falls completely silent at night, after all.”

“Yes... Achoo!”

As the two of them talked, Sayo started to feel a little cold and gave a cute sneeze. It was late spring, so the nights were still a little chilly. That day had been rather warm, however, so Sayo was only wearing thin layers.

“Here you go, Sayo.” Rio took off his own jacket and covered her shoulders.

“...T-Thank you very much,” Sayo thanked him timidly. Rio couldn’t see her expression in the dark, but scarlet red was staining her cheeks.

“Shin must be hungry by now, so let’s hurry. He’ll worry if you’re too late,” Rio said, hastening his pace a little bit.

“...Okay,” Sayo replied with a conflicted expression. She wanted to be together with Rio for just a little bit longer.

A Maiden’s Woes

In wintertime, on the first night of Komomo’s stay in the village, Komomo took Aio — her personal assistant — and Ruri to visit the village chief’s bathhouse.

“This is a splendid bath. Did Sir Rio really make this all by himself?” Komomo asked Ruri with a look of awe as they entered.

“Yeah. Rio knows a lot about everything and is super crafty with his hands. He used spirit arts and built this in less than two weeks. It’s become an essential facility in our village,” Ruri answered with a hint of pride.

“There are multiple bathtubs, too,” Aoi said as she looked around the room with deep interest.

“Yes. Having a single big bath would make it much more difficult to change the water, so it’s done this way to make it easier to adjust for the number of people bathing.”

“I see.” Aio hummed at Ruri’s explanation, exceedingly impressed. “It was certainly made with a lot of thought behind it, then.”

“Now that Rio’s filled the hot water for us, let’s get in before it cools. Otherwise, your body will get cold, too. Uugh, so chilly.” Ruri immediately headed towards the washing area.

“We have to wash our bodies first, right?”

“Allow me to wash your back, Lady Komomo.”

Komomo and Aoi followed after Ruri.

“I can wash your back next!” Komomo said to Ruri.

“Ahaha. Thank you, Komomo.”

When the sociable Ruri and overly-friendly Komomo were brought together, the two had become fast friends on the first day. They already opened up to each other enough to speak fondly to each other.

“Ruri, did I miss any spots?”

“It’s fine. Thank you, Komomo,” Ruri said after Komomo had washed her back thoroughly.

“Then, I’ll wash your front next,” Komomo said, winding her arms around Ruri’s chest from behind and hesitantly moving the towel.

“Huh...? Ah, huh?! W-Wait a minute! Komomo?!” Ruri started giggling at the ticklish sensation. Suddenly, Komomo’s hands stopped.

“...Hmph. They’re big,” she murmured.

“A-Ahaha. I’m going to ask just to be sure, but what are you talking about?”

“Your chest! Even though you’re only five years apart from me...” Komomo pouted her lips somewhat unhappily.

“W-Well, you’re still growing, Komomo.”

“...Really?”

“Y-Yup! You are. Right, Aoi?” Ruri nodded forcefully with a panicked face and turned to Aoi for help.

“Y-Yes. That’s right, Lady Komomo. I was about as big as you when I was your age,” Aoi said, bobbing her head enthusiastically.

“But... Even though Aoi’s several years older than Ruri, Ruri’s bigger than Aoi?”

“Ugh...”

The shock was enough to freeze Aoi’s hands from where they were washing Komomo’s back. She then brought both her hands up to cup her own chest.

“A-Ahaha. Well, individual results may vary.” Ruri evaded the point with a bitter smile.

“...I heard that lords prefer women with larger chests. Do you think Sir Rio is the same?” Komomo questioned in a somewhat worried way.

“L-Lady Komomo?! Why would you ask something like that?!” Aoi asked, taken aback.

“Aoi, now is not the time to point out trivial matters like that. What’s important here is Sir Rio’s preferences. What do you think, Ruri?” Komomo shook her head resolutely, pressing Ruri further.

“Huh? Ahaha. Umm, who knows...?” Ruri tilted her head stiffly and gave a dry laugh. Komomo’s expression darkened with sadness.

“Ah, t-then I’ll ask Rio next time I see him! Aha, ahaha...” Ruri promised for some reason, most likely because of the awkwardness rising within her.

“Really?!” Komomo’s expression bloomed brightly.

Ruri nodded with a shrill voice. “Y-Yeah. B-But I’m only going to ask. I don’t know whether he’ll answer or not...”

G-Geez, why am I agreeing to this so easily?! This is too embarrassing to ask! Ah, what am I going to do?! How am I going to ask him?!

Ruri was full of regret.

Cold Bath

During the first summer of Rio’s stay in the village, there was a day where they experienced a heatwave rarely seen in recent years. The villagers suspended their farm work and hid away inside their homes.

“Uugh, it’s hot.” Ruri sat on a cushion in the living room and fanned the chest area of her kimono.

“Ruri. That’s unsightly. What would Rio think if he came in?” Yuba scolded, furrowing her brows.

“It’s fine. I’ll fix it as soon as he comes in.”

“Good grief...”

“Where is Rio, anyway?”

“Who knows. He didn’t say he was going out somewhere, so maybe he’s in his room?”

Neither of them had any clues as to Rio’s location, but the front door opened and none other than Rio appeared.

“H-Huh? Rio, did you go out?” Ruri flinched and pulled her clothes straight in a fluster.

Ruri’s chest area entered his gaze for a moment, but Rio casually averted his gaze. “...No. I was doing my daily training in the garden, and then I took a cold bath in the bathhouse.”

“Eeh? You should rest on a day this hot. But a cold bath... I see, a cold bath. That’s right, that’s a good plan! Yup!”

Ruri had widened her eyes at the thought of Rio swinging his sword in the heat wave, but when she heard about the cold bath, she stood up vigorously as though she had had an epiphany. The momentum made her drawn-together kimono fall open at the chest once more.

“Erm... Then, do you want to get in the bathtub? I can prepare it for you right away.” Rio whipped around in an instant and walked outside the front door.

“Eh? Ah, erm, yeah! Please! Ahaha... Sorry.” Ruri grinned apologetically and properly fixed her messy clothing.

“This child is so much trouble,” Yuba sighed in exasperation. Yuba gave Ruri a harsh lesson on the ways of behaving like a lady, then Ruri headed for the bathhouse after finally being released several minutes later.

“Geez, today’s incident was just an accident. I might have been careless a few times when Rio came, but still... It’s all because of the heat wave today. I have to lift my spirits and get into that cold bath… It really is too hot today...” Ruri pouted her lips, venting her dissatisfaction. As she fanned her chest area to cool down as she usually did, she reached the bathhouse. Then, when she reached a hand out to the bathhouse door, Rio exited the bathhouse.

“Ah, Ruri. I just finished the preparations. Go... ahead...” When he saw Ruri fanning her chest, he froze in surprise.

“A-Ahaha... S-Sorry, Rio,” Ruri apologized, hiding her chest with a twitching smile.

“N-No. I’m the one who’s sorry...” Rio apologized awkwardly.

“R-Right. You were supposed to be here. I really am being careless, aren’t I? Ah, keep this a secret from Granny. She just got mad at me earlier.” Ruri put her hands together and pleaded earnestly at Rio, as though in prayer.

“Sure, I don’t mind, but... Shouldn’t it be the opposite? With me saying ‘sorry.’”

Ruri tilted her head in contemplation. “Huh? Hmm. Now that you mention it, maybe? But it’s my fault — I was being careless,” she said, grinning shyly.

“Haha. I’m going to go now, so cool yourself down to your heart’s content.”

“Yeah. Thank you... Ah, Rio. Do you want to get in, too?” Ruri asked inquisitively.

Rio shook his head bluntly. “No.”

“Ahaha, just kidding.” Ruri laughed flatly.

“Please, take your time.” Rio smiled somewhat happily and took his leave. Then, just as he arrived at the front door, Ruri screamed.

“H-Hyah! So cold! R-Rio! Make it hotter!”

...Guess I cooled it a little too much. Rio turned on his heel with a wry smile. He was met with the sight of a completely unguarded Ruri once again, but that’s another story for another day.

Chapter 3: Turmoil

Several more months passed since Rio began his stay in the village. The harvest season for upland rice had just begun, and it was the busiest time of the entire year. At this time of year, even the hunters — who normally went hunting in the mornings — helped in the fields instead.

Of course, Rio was no exception.

At the moment, he was swinging his hoe with all his might as he plowed the field. The monotony of the activity had caused calluses to develop on both his hands. They had cropped up in areas that differed from the ones that appeared when he used his sword. However, in his life as Amakawa Haruto, he had helped on his family farm throughout all of elementary and middle school, so Rio was used to the actions required to plow the rice fields. The farmers of the village were in awe of him.

A faint feeling of grief would occasionally pass through him at the thought of his father and grandparents, but as he continued to work, he felt strangely at peace.

Then, after work had progressed past a certain point...

“Hey, it’s time for a break! Lunch is served — everyone gather around!” Ruri yelled loudly so that all the working men would stop.

The villagers usually had two meals a day — once in the morning and once at night — but during opportunities like this, the whole village would gather to have lunch together. Working all morning would naturally cause them to feel hungry, so all the men unanimously headed toward the village square where food was being distributed.

“Here’s your miso soup and pickled vegetables. You can take up to two onigiri per person. Also, Rio provided the salt, so make sure you all thank him!” Ruri informed the villagers that were lined up to receive food as she set the tables. All the women and family men wore pleasant smiles as they thanked Rio, who was nearby.

“Hey. Make sure you all thank Rio, too.” The younger men tried to take the food gloomily and silently, but Ruri pouted her lips and reprimanded them. Sayo nodded in agreement from where she was setting the table beside Ruri.

The boys clicked their tongues and murmured a word of thanks to Rio, then hurriedly moved away and gathered in a group amongst themselves and filled their stomachs with onigiri. Their eyes widened in surprise at the taste when they realized how generously the salt was used.

“Well... I guess it’s better than in the past. They can at least say thank you, now. Sorry, Rio.” Ruri sighed in exasperation and apologized with a bitter smile as she looked at Rio beside her. He wasn’t moving to join the herds of people, but was waiting until the crowds had dispersed.

“It’s all right,” Rio said, giving a brief shake of his head.

“Okay, we should eat too before it gets cold. Everyone’s waiting, too,” Ruri suggested.

A small distance away, a group of girls were calling for Ruri.

“Okay. Then I will—”

“U-Umm! Sir Rio, would you like to eat with us? You wouldn’t be intruding at all!”

Rio had been looking around and thinking of joining a group of the elderly and older married couples, when Sayo stopped him in a fluster.

“Good idea — I’m starving. Let’s hurry,” Ruri agreed, and quickly moved toward the gathering of girls. Rio was apprehensive about being the only man in a group of the village’s young girls, fearing he would be antagonized further by the younger men of the village. However, Sayo was meekly waiting beside him to move together, so he couldn’t broach the idea of eating with anyone else in this situation.

Nonetheless, villagers who were older and married, like Dola and Ume, were sitting right next to the girls, so Rio reconsidered his thoughts and decided there was no need to concern himself.

“All right. Let’s go, Sayo.”

“Okay!” Sayo nodded happily.

Rio started to walk toward where the girls were with Sayo trotting along behind him.

Meanwhile, Ruri had already reached the others, and called for Rio in a joking tone. “Hurry up, you two!” she said, and the other girls joined in.

“That’s right — we’re tired of waiting already!”

“It’s not fair for Sayo to hog Sir Rio all to herself!”

And so on. They began to crowd around Rio and talk noisily.

“Hello, everyone. Haven’t you eaten yet?” Rio asked, noticing that the girls had yet to touch their own food.

“We were waiting for you. We can’t let Sayo monopolize Sir Rio all to herself, after all,” one smart girl said, shooting Sayo a playful look.

“I see. I’m sorry to have kept you waiting, then. Please allow me to join you.” Rio bowed apologetically and sat down at an empty place.

“I-I’m not monopolizing him! I just thought the food would taste better if we ate all together, so I was waiting for Sir Rio... Umm...”

Sayo had frozen in shock for a moment, but the embarrassment eventually welled up and caused her to object with a bright red face.

“All right, all right. Basically, Sayo wanted to eat with her Sir Rio no matter what. Got it.” The girl who had been teasing Sayo nodded in mock understanding.

“N-No! It’s not like that! ...Ah, no, that’s not it... it’s not that I don’t want to eat with Sir Rio...” Sayo had reflexively denied it, but she hurriedly attempted to take back her words and explain herself to Rio.

“It’s all right. I understand.” Unsure of how to react, Rio simply forced a smile on his face.

In the meantime, the girls were watching Sayo’s flustered disposition with pleased smiles.

“Now now, everyone. Go easy on her. Sayo’s nearly reached her limit,” Ruri said to the girls exasperatedly.

Sayo glared at all of the girls with a resentful look in her teary eyes. Yet, despite her gaze, she seemed more like a small, cornered animal, so there was no impact behind her expression. If anything, it just caused others to feel more protective of her.

It was almost adorable enough to make everyone want to tease her even more...

“Fine. Well, she’s not the only one who wants to eat lunch with Sir Rio. We all do,” the cheerful girl who had been teasing Sayo said innocently. The other girls nodded along in agreement.

“Thank you... I’m glad to hear that. But may I ask you to stop calling me ‘Sir Rio’? I’m not in any superior position deserving of that title, so it makes me feel rather awkward,” Rio said why a shy grin.

“Eeeh? But ‘Sir Rio’ kind of gives off this high class aura.”

“Yup, yup. It’s like you were raised differently compared to the other men in this village.”

“Right? As soon as you mention ‘Sir Rio’ to them, they get grumpy. How gross.”

“It’s hard to think of them as men, too.”

“Ahaha, don’t compare them! Sir Rio doesn’t deserve that dishonor.”

“You’re right. I’m sorry, Sir Rio.”

And so on — the girls continued to chatter energetically and noisily. Their conversation moved from one topic to the next, until they had completely forgotten about teasing Sayo and about Rio’s request. It seemed as though he’d have to endure being referred to as “Sir Rio” for a little while longer. His shoulders slumped.

Although, Rio really wasn’t one to talk, either, having been told by the girls many times he did not need to speak so politely around them. Perhaps this had leveled the playing field.

A bit further away from Rio and the girls, Dola and Ume were sitting together sipping at their tea, having finished their meals. Both were smiling pleasantly, watching Rio and the noisy girls talk excitedly amongst themselves.

“Hahaha, as expected of Rio’s good looks. It’s like looking at my old self.”

“Are you saying Rio’s like your old self? Don’t kid yourself.” Ume flatly rejected Dola’s statement.

“Hey, now. What makes you say that? I’m being completely serious here.”

“I absolutely do not recall ever marrying a man that gorgeous. It’s rude to even consider comparing Rio to you. What a joke, am I right?”

“Wha— Hey! What are you saying to your own husband?!”

“You’re complete opposites in both appearance and personality, and you were nowhere near that mature when you were young. I’d say you weren’t much different from the young boys that are jealous of Rio right now. Overflowing with brute strength, but with no knowledge of how to hunt properly.”

“Geh... You just keep running your mouth. W-Well, he has been traveling the world at his young age, after all. He must have gone through quite a few hardships himself. I admit, I may not have been as accomplished as him when I was young...” Unable to refute Ume’s words, Dola swallowed his words reluctantly and nodded.

“So you do realize it! Ah, but now that you mention it, there was another man in our village who was like Rio, too — and it wasn’t you, of course.” Ume said, looking up at the sky in the distance.

“Huh? Since when was there someone in our villa... Aah, that guy, huh?” Dola was about to deny there being another similar man, when he suddenly seemed to remember something. His expression turned faintly unpleasant, but nostalgic all the same.

“Even though you could never win against him, you were burning with a sense of rivalry. Just like Shin does right now.” Ume cackled with laughter.

“Shut up. You were rejected by that guy, too. He said he was leaving the village to become a soldier.”

“All the girls my age confessed to him at the time. None of them succeeded, of course.”

“Figures. He wasn’t the type to settle for a woman from some country town like this,” Dola said, nodding with a beaming smile.

“Oh? It seems you have quite a high opinion of Zen after all.”

“Hmph. Shut up.”

“I wonder what he’s up to right now... Do you think he has a child yet?”

“Who knows. If he did...” Dola shook his head unhappily and bit his tongue out of a sense of discomfort.

“If he did?” Ume urged him to continue with a doubtful look.

“...If he did, then the kid would probably be around the age of the young folks in this village. That, or younger. Either way, that man isn’t coming back. There’s no point in thinking about it,” Dola answered bluntly.

“Well, I suppose you’re right.” Ume nodded a bit sadly.

◇◇◇

One week later, when the bustle of the village harvests had finally settled down...

Rio was making his way home after finishing his work for the day when he ran into Yuba on the road, just before sunset.

“Ah, Rio. Perfect timing. I had something I wanted to ask of you. Let’s discuss it as we walk home,” Yuba said once they were within speaking distance, prompting them to resume their journey home together.

“So, what did you want to discuss?” Rio spoke up first.

“Yes...” Yuba nodded, before beginning to speak. “Whenever the rice harvesting season comes to an end, the kingdom dispatches a tax officer. Once they get here, they officially decide the amount of rice to pay for the annual land tax and we distribute the rest among our food supplies. Anything that’s leftover is taken to the capital to be sold. You know all this already, yes?”

“Yes, I’ve been told about it.”

“Good, that makes this simpler. We’re in the middle of deciding who shall be on the transportation squad, and I was thinking of asking you to escort them, since you have experience traveling alone. It’s rare that anything’ll happen, but I can’t say for sure that it won’t be dangerous. Are you up for the task?” Yuba asked cautiously.

“Sure, I don’t mind. I’d be happy to,” Rio immediately consented with a nod.

“That would be a great help. Sorry for troubling you.” Yuba smiled broadly, relieved of her anxieties.

“It’s no big deal. Something like this is no problem at all.” Rio smiled faintly, giving a small shrug of his shoulders.

“Thanks to you, life in this village has gotten so much better. All the villagers are very grateful to you. You’ve taught us how to create useful tools and use new techniques in our farming. At this rate, next year’s harvest will be huge, so you’ve truly been such a big help.”

“I don’t think anything has changed that dramatically, but your harvest rates should stabilize more than they did before.” The corner of Rio’s mouth curled up into a small grin.

“I look forward to it.” Yuba smiled pleasantly.

Then, as they neared the village chief’s house... “Take that back, asshole!” someone yelled loudly. It was coming from the direction of the house.

Rio and Yuba looked at each other.

“Is there a fight?” Yuba murmured suspiciously.

“I’m going to see what’s going on.” Rio prepared to jog ahead to the chief’s house first.

“Wait up, I’ll go too.” Yuba called Rio back, following him at a faster pace than usual. Thus, the two of them swiftly headed down the road toward the village chief’s house.

◇◇◇

A few moments before Yuba and Rio arrived at the house, right outside, two groups of men were glaring at each other. One group was composed of the youths of the village — including Shin — while the other was a group of young men that Rio was unfamiliar with.

The village boys were winning in terms of numbers, but the opposing side had one person that was particularly large; he looked like he’d be quite formidable in a fist fight. Furthermore, hidden behind the youths of the village — as though they were being protected by them — were several village girls (including Sayo and Ruri) in light clothing.

It was possible that they were on their way to the bathhouse next to the village chief’s house, or they had just come out.

“Who the hell do you think you are, Gon, walking around like you own this place?! You even had the nerve to march straight into the bathhouse,” Shin said, glaring hatefully at the giant named Gon.

“Huh? I came to visit the village chief as a guest. There was a shed I didn’t recognize just sitting there, so I went to investigate it. Since when did you even make a bathhouse? But, I see, so that was why...”

Understanding the situation, Gon directed a lecherous gaze toward the girls in their light clothing. The men surrounding him also had their gazes fixed on the girls as they smiled creepily.

“Don’t look at them with your disgusting eyes!” Shin yelled.

“Why not? It’s not hurting anyone. Who cares if we look — or is your woman among them?” Gon laughed at him condescendingly.

“My little sister is!”

“Oh? You have a little sister? Which one?” Gon inspected the group of girls closely. Sayo’s frame shook with a start.

“Sayo, hide behind me,” Ruri whispered, hiding Sayo behind her back, but Gon seemed to have gotten a clear view of her already.

“She’s still a brat, but she’s a pretty thing, ain’t she? Why don’t you introduce us, dear brother in law?” he said, grinning.

“Fuck you!” Shin raged, moments away from hitting Gon.

“Hold on, Shin! Don’t!” Ruri ran forward in a hurry, grabbing his arm to stop him.

“L-Let me go, Ruri! This asshole won’t stop until I teach him a lesson!”

“You can’t just let him stir you up so easily! It’d be a huge problem if you punched him over something as small as this! No matter how rotten he is, he’s still the son of another village chief. You don’t want to cause Sayo any trouble, right?!”

“Guh...” Shin relented weakly, his face flushed with frustration.

Gon let out a disappointed sigh and tried to provoke him further. “Aww, you don’t have to hold back just because I’m the son of another village chief, you know?”

Shin, however, kept his head down and stood his ground.

“Tch, coward.” Gon clicked his tongue, unamused. He fixed his attention from Shin to Ruri instead. “Well, whatever. Ruri, you’ve grown into a quite a beauty... I almost didn’t recognize you, there.”

“Yeah, right. So, what did you want with our village?” Ruri asked, easily brushing away Gon’s nonsense.

“Let me stay at your place. We were on our way to the capital to sell our village’s products when our cargo carriage broke down. It’ll take all of tomorrow to repair.”

“I understand wanting to repair your broken-down carriage, but why do you need to stay at our place to do that?”

“Because I’m a guest of your village, and the son of another village chief? I’d expect an appropriate reception.”

“Then we’ll lend you one of our guest cabins, so you can stay there instead. Unfortunately, we don’t have any spare rooms in our house to lend to you.” Ruri shook her head curtly and refused Gon’s demands.

“Hey, now. You shouldn’t treat your potential future husband so coldly, you know?”

“...H-Huh? Don’t spout such ridiculous nonsense! How disgusting!” Ruri held herself steadily, but Gon’s words made her body tremble.

“Oi, Ruri?! What does he mean?! Are you getting married to this bastard?!” Shin asked her in a panic.

“I have no idea what he’s going on about! Why would I marry someone like that?!” Ruri replied, as though it was her first time hearing this.

“Didn’t you know? The only heir of your village chief right now is Ruri. Which means... according to tradition, Ruri will be the next village chief. But since you have to get married and govern the village with your husband, you can’t stay unmarried as a village chief. That’s why I’m offering myself up as Ruri’s husband,” Gon said brazenly, with no trace of any shame.

“That’s bullshit! You can’t just decide that by yourself!” Shin, who had been out of the line of fire for a while, was unable to listen any further to Gon’s excessive statements and yelled out loudly.

“I’m not deciding, I’m offering. And it should be my freedom to offer myself up, no? Outsiders like you have no right to protest.”

“As a member of the village, I won’t allow it!” Shin yelled, and the boys around him echoed their agreement.

“That’s right!”

“Hah? None of you even have a claim on Ruri. What is this, collective jealousy? What a bunch of pussies.” Gon let out a mocking sigh.

“Take that back, asshole!” Unable to bear it any further, Shin took a swing at Gon.

“Let’s follow Shin!” the other boys yelled, breathing harshly through their noses. They’d lost their tempers, too.

“Ah, hold it, all of you! Shin! Stop right there!” Ruri tried to stop them, but her voice no longer reached their ears.

“Ha! Now it’s finally getting interesting. Come at me: I’ll show you how much more powerful I am!”

“Shut your mouth, you bastard!” Unaffected by their difference of stature — he was at least 20 centimeters shorter in height — Shin sprung forward. His fist was on a collision course with Gon’s face, but Gon easily grabbed the incoming punch. He looked down at Shin with a surprised expression.

“Oi. You use spirit arts, don’t you? Is this the best you can do when you’ve strengthened yourself?” He didn’t look like he was feeling any resistance from the fist at all.

“W-What the hell did you say?!” Shin became worked up and put more strength into his captured fist, but his arm didn’t even budge, despite the fact that he was using spirit arts to strengthen his body.

“You’re not even worth fighting,” Gon muttered under his breath, extending his other hand to simply grab Shin by the neck. He then lifted Shin’s body into the air as though it weighed nothing.

“Wha— Guh... Gah...!” Shin struggled in pain. He tried to tear Gon’s arm away from him, but he couldn’t even make it budge.

“S-Shin! S-Stop! Stop it, please!” Seeing her brother in pain made Sayo run forward in a panic. Her voice was shrill and her body was shaking slightly. When her eyes met Gon’s, she timidly directed her gaze downward to avoid eye contact.

“Ah? Well, if you absolutely insist, then I wouldn’t be against keeping him like this, I suppose...” Pleased with himself, Gon huffed through his nose and looked down at her triumphantly.

“That’s enough! What are you all doing?!” Yuba’s voice suddenly echoed over everything; she had finally arrived after hearing the commotion, with Rio in tow beside her. Gon clicked his tongue quietly and looked at Yuba.

“Hey. It’s been a while, Old Lady Yuba. Sorry for the commotion — we were just bickering when this guy here suddenly tried to punch me,” he replied, gaze fixed on Shin, who he still had by the neck.

“If you’re sorry, then release him. I don’t care if you’re the son of another chief — any more fights in my village and I’ll make you leave. No ifs, ands, or buts,” Yuba said bluntly, locking her sharp glare on Gon.

“...All right, all right. I wasn’t interested in puny punks like him anyway.” Gon released the hand he had around Shin’s neck.

“Koff, koff... Ugh...” Shin’s body collapsed, folding over in a coughing fit.

“Are you okay, Shin?!”

Sayo supported Shin’s body in a panic. She placed her hands around his throat and cast a healing spirit art to soothe the pain. Several seconds later, Shin was able to breathe normally again.

“Y-You bastard...” he glared at Gon.

“Ha! You need your precious little sister to protect you? How pathetic,” Gon sneered triumphantly.

“Stop it, you two! Shin, get out of here and cool your head,” Yuba scolded.

“Guh...” Shin held back his words and hung his head in frustration. Sayo supported her brother by the shoulder and helped him move toward the back.

“C-Come on, Shin, let’s go.”

“I’ll help you, Sayo.” Ruri approached them and helped Sayo support her brother’s body up from the other side.

After Shin had retreated, Yuba spoke to Gon, trying to settle the situation at hand. “So, why have you come calling today? Don’t tell me you’re here just to pick fights.”

“We were just on our way to the capital to sell our village’s products and decided to drop by, since our horse-drawn cargo carriage unfortunately broke down. I came to visit you, the village chief, to ask for permission to stay in the village in the meantime.”

“And how did that end up causing a fight?”

“...That new shed over there piqued my interest. When we approached it, the boys from your village appeared and yelled at us. Which... then turned to this,” Gon answered, shrugging his shoulders.

“Granny, we were all bathing at the time. One of the girls noticed they were approaching the bathhouse and screamed...” Ruri explained.

“I see. So Gon and the others were mistaken for peeping toms and ruffians.” Yuba nodded in understanding.

Gon denied the accusation without delay. “Just so you know, we weren’t aware that the shed was for bathing. I was just curious about the impressive little shed that wasn’t here last time.”

“Well, I’ll accept the fact you didn’t know what the shed was for. However, that does not excuse the fact that you trespassed onto someone else’s property to conduct your own investigation, uninvited.” Yuba analyzed the situation calmly.

Rio agreed with Yuba. Thinking there was no need for him to step forward, he had been watching silently from the sidelines.

“Tch. Well, I guess that part was my fault.”

Gon expressed remorse with a click of his tongue. He seemed to find Yuba’s control of the situation difficult to deal with, but he wasn’t about to take it lying down.

“You know,” he began. “Those guys were probably trying to peep on the women’s bath for real, don’t you think? Why else would they run into us so conveniently in front of the chief’s house? Am I right, Shin?” He set his eyes on Shin’s group with a grin.

“W-Wha?! N-No! We only came running because we heard Gon’s group had appeared in the village and were heading for the chief’s house! And Sayo said she was going to bathe!” Shin denied the accusation in a panic; he seemed to have recovered enough to speak, at least. The other boys also echoed their agreement after their shock wore off.

Yuba heaved a tired sigh. “All right, I understand now. Is there anything else anyone would like to add?” She asked everyone present.

No one spoke up.

“Then, this matter ends here. Gon, I apologize for how Shin’s misunderstanding caused the situation to grow out of hand. However, your actions were too rash and violent. I’ll allow you to stay in a guest cabin on the outskirts of the village, but you are forbidden from going out needlessly. Got it?” Yuba gave her ruling in a tone that didn’t allow for any further objections.

“Fine, whatever. Later, Old Lady Yuba.”

Gon gave an exaggerated sigh and started walking away, with his group of followers hurrying after his departing back. They made their way down the road Rio and Yuba had just come up from.

Hm? Was there someone like this in the village before?

As he walked, Gon noticed that there was someone unfamiliar standing next to Yuba — Rio. He narrowed his eyes and inspected the boy’s face. Rio returned his look with a cool stare, watching to see if Gon would try and start something else.

Hmph. With a refined face like that, he’s probably another pansy. I don’t like the look of him.

Seeing the way Rio stared back at him without hesitation made Gon furrow his brow slightly. But his expression immediately changed to a wicked smirk, as though he had suddenly come up with a fantastic idea.

Gon had been walking with his shoulders squared, but he suddenly directed his attention away from his destination. He feigned carelessness as he veered off-course and crashed into Rio at the last minute. Their upper bodies collided with each other.

“Oops, my mista—?!”

Gon, who exceeded Rio in both height and weight, recoiled as though he had walked into a wall. The unexpected impact made him stumble to regain his footing, and he widened his eyes in utter shock.

“A-Are you all right, Mister Gon? What happened?” One of the men walking behind Gon asked with surprise in his eyes. He couldn’t see what had happened from behind.

“Uh? Ah...” Gon was still a little dazed. He looked between his body and Rio’s in comparison, unable to comprehend what had occurred.

“I see that your muscles are quite toned, but it seems your long journey has made you weary. The sun will be setting soon; may I suggest you retire to your lodgings to rest?” Rio said eloquently, giving an insincere smile with no emotion behind it at all.

“...Tch. Let’s go, everyone.”

Gon seemed to sense there was something strange about Rio, but convinced himself that it was just his imagination. That was how confident he was in his own physical strength.

With his followers in tow, Gon departed for real this time.

Once their party were completely out of sight, the young men and women of the village immediately relaxed all of their tension at once, and heaved a collective sigh of relief.

“Good grief. All this unnecessary ruckus,” Yuba sighed in exasperation.

“G-Granny. Shin and the others were just trying to protect us. So, umm, don’t blame them too much, okay?” Ruri tried to defend them in a hurry.

“I know that, of course. I figured the one that caused the commotion was probably that wild child. After his parents gave up on him, he never received any proper discipline, and only uses his craftiness to get by, so he’s quite the troublemaker. That being said, these boys were also at fault for getting worked up so easily.” Yuba glared at Shin and the others.

“Ugh...”

After being rash enough to land the first blow, not to mention being beaten on top of that, Shin and the others were left feeling guilty and unable to object to Yuba.

“For now, I want each and every one of you to go home without any more fuss. I forbade them from going out, but don’t let down your guard. Inform the others in your neighborhood, too. And make sure you let me know immediately if anything unusual occurs,” Yuba instructed, making everyone exchange glances before they agreed timidly.

After a while, the girls returned to the bathhouse to finish changing, then came back out. With their preparations complete, everyone started to move about and make their way home.

However, two people remained frozen where they stood. It was Shin and Sayo. Sayo still seemed frightened after the events from before, as her body was still faintly trembling.

“What’s the matter? You two should get home too,” Yuba said.

“...Hey, Gran. I have a request. Could you please let Sayo stay at your place tonight? As you know, it’s just us living in our house, and I made a fool of myself earlier. Our place isn’t that far from where those guys are staying, so she’s probably feeling anxious too, so... She’d feel better if she stayed with Ruri and Gran and... him... I think.” Shin frowned in embarrassment as he bowed his head at Yuba. He snuck a glance at Rio for a second, but immediately tore his eyes away again.

Yuba seemed to be struck by this, as her eyes widened slightly. “Oh? What’s this? It’s strange to see such an admirable attitude coming from you, even if it is for Sayo’s sake. Did getting beaten up become a good lesson for you?” She laughed heartily at Shin.

“S-Shut up! I got too fired up before and caused some trouble, but that’s not it! Are you going to let her stay or what?!” Shin objected, blushing bright red.

“Sure, I don’t mind. You’re right, after all. Sayo, stay at our place tonight.” Yuba gave her permission and looked at Sayo, who was standing very still in fear.

“Huh? Ah... Is it really okay?” Sayo asked in a daze.

“It’s fine. Judging by your state, you would’ve been too scared to sleep alone anyway. Sleep with Ruri tonight. ...Oh, or did you want to sleep with Rio instead?” Yuba asked cheekily and nodded with a wry smile.

“...I-I’m fine! I’ll sleep with Ruri!” Sayo flushed, shaking her head furiously. She seemed a little bit more like her usual self.

“Is that so? Then, all right. As for you, Shin — you can stay here tonight, too. Gon may be harboring a grudge toward you in particular.”

“I... Fine, then. Thanks.” Shin hesitated for a moment, but nodded obediently in the end.

“Okay, we’ll need two more plates set for dinner tonight! Let’s get cooking, shall we?” Yuba said, trying to brighten the mood, before going inside the house in high spirits.

“Right. Let’s go, everyone,” Ruri said, looking at the other three.

“I’ll help cook the rice!” Sayo offered eagerly.

“I have some business to attend to first, so please return without me,” Rio said, voicing his intention to stay outside.

“Huh? Business?” Ruri asked in confusion.

“I’d like to set up some security measures, just in case.”

“Hmm? Then, uuh... please do?”

“Yes, leave it to me.”

Ruri didn’t seem to understand, but Rio gave her a strained smile and nodded.

“Okay, then. We don’t want to get in your way, so we’ll head in first. You too, Shin.”

“...Yeah.”

Shin looked like he wanted to say something more to Rio, but walked away hesitantly at Ruri’s call.

◇◇◇

That night, just as the villagers were having their supper, Gon and his followers were having drinks in the cabin that had been lent to them. Spread out on the floor before them was their dinner, along with various preserved side dishes; it was all bland, with no seasoning at all.

“It sure is boring around here, boss. Nothing interesting at all, just like our village,” a man of small stature said as he poured Gon’s drink for him.

“Well, the operation starts tomorrow at midnight. We have to lay low until then, especially since we now have a good reason to stay inside.” Gon chugged the poured alcohol with a grin.

“Haha. You’re amazing, boss. By causing a commotion in the beginning and laying low afterward, those idiots will lower their guard. It’s downright wicked,” The small man sitting next to Gon said.

“Well, it’s all so that I can have my way with Ruri, after all.”

“Haha! Ruri’s a beauty, but I think Shin’s little sister looked like quite the catch, too.”

“Hear, hear! I see you’re quite the hedonist, huh? Well, her face wasn’t bad, and the fact that she’s that bastard’s little sister makes it all the better. I suppose she’d be a good second priority after Ruri.” Gon heartily carved a perverted grin on his face.

“Let me have a taste of her too, boss.”

“Sure — if you’re OK with my leftovers.”

“All right!” As soon as Gon gave his permission, his followers cheered vigorously.

All the men present were considered questionable in the village they came from. The group consisted of second sons or lower — those who would never inherit their family businesses — that had banded together to follow the beat of their own drums. At the head of the group was their leader, Gon.

Gon was the son of their village chief, but like the others, he was a second son and had been raised as a spare ever since childhood. However, Gon was unable to sit back quietly and accept his role as a secondary human like the others.

Perhaps it was due to his education, or perhaps it was because he was still raised somewhat lovingly as a village chief’s son, but his personality developed into a clever and spoiled one as he grew up.

Gon’s body was well-built, he had a considerable amount of physical strength, and had the talent for spirit arts. His specialty was the spirit arts for physical ability and physical body enhancement — the worst possible combination. Since he was ten years old, none of the adult villagers could stand up to him, which made others treat Gon as an outcast.

Now, he was eighteen. At some point along the way, Gon started to gather second sons like him on his side, establishing his own power in the village. As of late, his influence in the village had grown so strong that not even the village chief could touch him. Even when he caused trouble, it was difficult to punish him.

Under normal circumstances, there was no way a group of hooligans like Gon would be selected for the trade squad going to the capital; however, the villagers were unable to refuse the demands of Gon’s gang, ultimately allowing them the role of escorting the goods. They hadn’t even noticed what the gang had been secretly plotting behind their backs...

Recently, the villagers had been trying to persuade Gon’s gang into joining the kingdom’s army, but Gon knew they were just trying to tactfully chase them out of the village. Because of that, Gon devised a plan for them to leave on their own terms.

However, the world wasn’t so easy to live in that they could spontaneously leave their village with nothing but their group. They needed to secure their relocation destination in advance, along with food, clothes, and shelter.

That was when Yuba’s village caught Gon’s eye. If he became Ruri’s husband, then he would become a legitimate village chief.

Yuba’s village neighbored Gon’s village, allowing them to interact fairly often, so Gon knew that Ruri was Yuba’s one and only heir. It was truly a once in a lifetime opportunity that had fallen into his lap.

Most importantly, Ruri’s appearance was Gon’s type to a T.

Regardless, it was clear that if he went about his plan head-on, Ruri would reject him. The fact that Gon decided to try a more subtle approach without hesitation showed how twisted he truly was.

“We went through all that trouble of smashing the carriage, too. Better take our time repairing it tomorrow.” Gon grinned with joy at the thought of tomorrow night.

◇◇◇

The next morning arrived without incident, despite the fact that uninvited company had arrived the day before. So far, Gon and his gang had kept their promise, avoiding contact with the villagers and focusing on the repairs of their horse carriage. Since that was the case, the villagers cast Gon out of the forefront of their minds.

Although they had passed the peak of the harvest season, there was still plenty of work for all the villagers to do; they had to start preparing large amounts of food to be preserved for the winter, and products had to be prepared to be taken to the capital, too. Because of this, the villagers had been bustling about energetically since early in the morning. By the time noon had passed, they had completely forgotten their wariness for Gon’s group. As the sun slowly began to set, they wrapped up their work for the day and headed home.

Rio finished the work allocated to him rather early today as well, so he headed back home ahead of anyone else. Yuba was already home, so the two of them decided to rest for a short while before going about making supper. Then, just as the tea was poured, someone knocked on the front door.

“Is Lady Yuba present?” they called.

“I’ll see who it is.”

“Thank you.”

Rio hurriedly stood up after urging Yuba to stay seated and moved toward the front door. He opened the door to see Ume standing there.

“Good evening, Ume. Can I help you?”

“Rio. Sir Hayate has arrived, so I’m here to inform Lady Yuba.” Ume must have rushed over, as she was slightly out of breath.

“I’ve heard. I shall go meet him right away — is he at the storehouse already?” Yuba asked.

“Yes, along with his subordinates. I’ve told him to make himself at home in the spare guest cabins.”

“I see. Good job, Ume.” Yuba nodded, pleased. She changed into her outdoor shoes on the clay floor and moved to leave the house, but paused and turned back to Rio.

“Ah, that’s right. Rio — sorry to ask this of you, but could you add five to six more servings to tonight’s dinner? We’ll probably have some people join us for a meal tonight. I may call one of the village girls over to help,” Yuba requested.

“I understand... Leave it to me. Would it be better if the meal was a bit more extravagant? If so, I could go and hunt something right now...”

“Ooh, could I ask that of you? That would be great — thank you. And you can help yourself to the vegetable garden if you run low on ingredients.” Yuba smiled cheerfully, thanking Rio for his willingness to help.

Then, with Rio seeing her off, she left at a quick-footed pace, while Rio quickly cleaned up the tea set and headed out to the mountain to hunt. Since he was short on time, he decided to use the spirit arts he usually refrained from using when he hunted.

Rio kicked off the ground at the foot of the mountain and rose into the air with his wind spirit arts, arriving at the hunting grounds in the blink of an eye. If the villagers had witnessed that, their eyes would’ve grown to the size of saucers, and their jaws would’ve dropped to the ground.

After spotting a Lenou bird flying through the air with his enhanced vision, Rio closed in on it from above and beheaded it in one swing of his sword. Catching its body by the legs, he went about draining the blood while he hovered midair.

One down.

Lenou birds were wary creatures that didn’t typically flock together, but they were much easier to hunt in the air when their guard was down. With that in mind, Rio immediately spotted his next prey flying a little ways off from his current location, and quickly set off after it.

His hunt continued to progress smoothly after that, and he was able to finish it all — including cleanup — before the sun had fully set.

◇◇◇

After wrapping up the carriage repairs early and dumping the rest on their underlings and the villagers that had accompanied them, Gon’s gang were drinking away in the cabin that had been lent to them before the sun had even set.

Suddenly, the door to the cabin slammed open. All the gazes in the room shifted toward the door to see a boy in his teens standing there, panting.

“Hah... Hah...”

“Oh, what’s up? Has the carriage been repaired already?” A drunk Gon inquired heartily.

The boy was an underling of Gon’s gang and was often used to run errands for them, as he was the youngest of the group. He had been tasked with the supervision of the villagers repairing the carriage and helping out on Gon’s behalf.

“Ah, boss! This is bad! The tax officer is here in the village!” The boy yelled, causing the men around Gon to stir noisily.

Tax officers were special government officials. They were dispatched by the capital during harvest season to every village to collect taxes based on the amount of crops that were harvested. It was an official position that was given only to the most trusted people in the kingdom, and those who took on the role were masters in both literary and military arts. Calculations were required in order to conduct harvest inspections, and the officers had to have the strength to protect the collected tax from various dangers on the road. But, most importantly, they had to be people that wouldn’t abuse their privileges.

“...So what?” Gon asked in a sobered voice. He seemed to be aggravated that the mood of their drinking party had been ruined.

“N-No, it’s just, won’t the tax officer be staying at the village chief’s place? Even we can’t go up against a kingdom official. Maybe we should hold off on the boss’ plan...” the boy answered in a shrill voice.

“That doesn’t matter,” Gon replied unhappily and brought a cup filled with alcohol to his mouth.

The other men exchanged glances.

“But, boss. The tax officers are rumored to be really strong, aren’t they? There was once a guy who suppressed the uprising of a whole village single-handedly,” one of the men said hesitantly.

“Oh? Are you calling me weak?” Gon glared.

“No, of course not!” The man shook his head in a fluster.

“Besides, we’re going to head over once everyone’s asleep. Since it’s Old Lady Yuba we’re talking about, there’ll probably be alcohol involved. Even if it’s a tax officer, warrior, or just a peasant, once they’re drunk and asleep, they’ll be defenseless.”

“Well, that’s true... I-I guess you’re right.” Overpowered by Gon’s brimming self-confidence, the men regained their nerves.

“Obviously. It’s no different to what we’ve done before. Once our night crawling attempt is successful, Ruri will give up and accept her fate. If she protests, we’ll just threaten her. Really, if we wanted to make sure it goes off without a hitch, we could just kidnap her and bring her with us. That might make things easier, too, no?” Gon said with a lecherous grin.

Led on by his words, the other men chuckled with sinister laughter.

◇◇◇

Rio hurried home after his hunt, but no one else had returned yet, so he decided to wash off the scent of blood from his body first.

The main dish tonight would be Lenou; after washing up and mulling over various dish combinations for the menu, Rio headed toward the kitchen and finally got to work prepping ingredients. Before long, an enticing aroma wafted through the living room.

That was when Yuba came home, accompanied by a group of men, Ruri, and Sayo. The front entrance immediately became livelier.

“Welcome home,” Rio called out to Yuba and the others from the kitchen, which was located on the right side of the clay floor.

“We’re back. It smells especially good today.” Yuba smiled broadly at Rio, returning his greeting.

“Yeah, it smells great! What are you cooking, Rio?”

“Let me help you, Sir Rio!”

Ruri and Sayo hurried into the kitchen to help.

“Indeed, this is quite the wonderful aroma... Lady Yuba, was that boy always a member of this village?” A young gentleman asked, peering into the kitchen from the clay floor and looking at Rio as he spoke.

“That is Rio, the son of an old acquaintance of mine. He’s staying in our village right now,” Yuba said. Rio left the stove to Ruri and Sayo for the moment as he ducked out onto the clay floor to greet their guest.

“Good evening. My name is Rio — pleased to make your acquaintance.”

“Hello. My name is Saga Hayate, and I am the tax officer visiting this village. Behind me are my aides. It is nice to meet you.”

“Same here.”

Rio and the gentleman named Hayate exchanged their greetings. Despite Hayate’s stiff features, he was a pleasant young man with a refreshing aura about him. He had a splendid single-edged straight blade at his waist and wore an outfit similar to a finely-designed samurai outfit.

Age-wise, he seemed to be a few years Rio’s senior.

For the record, it was custom in the Yagumo region to name yourself from your family name first, making Saga his family name and Hayate his first name.

Rio and Hayate bowed at each other, each examining the other young man’s center of gravity and posture. They secretly determined that the other was no ordinary person.

“Now, let’s not stand around all day. Everyone, please come up to the living room and have a seat. Dinner will be ready soon.” Yuba stepped up into the living and urged Hayate’s party to follow.

“Thank you. We shall gratefully accept your offer.” Hayate bowed deeply and removed his footwear before stepping up into the living room.

“I shall return to the kitchen for now. Please excuse me, Yuba.”

“Yes, please do.” Yuba acknowledged Rio as he returned to the kitchen.

At the same time, Ruri came out of the kitchen into the living room.

“Here you go, everyone. Thank you for your hard work today.” Ruri smiled in a friendly manner as she poured tea for Hayate and the others.

“R-Right. Much obliged, Lady Ruri.” Hayate’s stiff attitude from earlier flipped completely as he offered Ruri his thanks; he had a strange awkwardness to his movements. He didn’t even attempt to make eye contact with Ruri, apparently feeling shy. Rio watched, the change in Hayate taking him by surprise.

“Ruri, you can stay here and keep everyone company,” Yuba ordered, putting Ruri in charge of giving the visitors a warm reception. Ruri had a bright and friendly personality, so she was perfect for the job. Yuba also had to remain with the visitors, which naturally left the cooking to Rio and Sayo.

Rio returned to the kitchen to resume cooking, and turned to Sayo. “Sorry for making you help so much, Sayo. Will Shin be okay for his meal today?” he asked with a guilty look.

“Yes. My brother will be eating dinner at Dola and Ume’s place tonight. It happens quite often when important visitors come, so please don’t let it bother you,” Sayo said happily, shaking her head.

“Did something good happen?” Rio inquired about Sayo’s good mood.

“Huh? Why do you ask?”

“It’s just that you look happy.”

Sayo tilted her head in confusion for a moment before she came to a realization.

“...Ah,” she grinned shyly, before hesitantly asking Rio: “...Is it that obvious?”

“Yes.” Rio nodded, making Sayo flush red.

“Umm, it’s a secret.”

“I see... Then I shall not pry any further.” Rio’s lips tugged upward in a bright smile. As long as Sayo was happy, he was glad.

“...Okay.” A conflicted expression flickered over Sayo’s face for a moment, but she nodded in assent.

“I’m sure everyone is hungry by now, so let’s hurry with the preparations.”

Sayo nodded at Rio’s suggestion. “Okay. But... I kind of want to take time to enjoy cooking together, too,” she mumbled under her breath.

Rio had already moved away, so the latter half of her sentence did not reach him.

◇◇◇

Less than an hour later, all of the cooking had been completed, and the table was set for dinner.

“This is quite the extravagant meal. I wasn’t expecting to be treated to your precious stockpile of meat... And this isn’t preserved meat either. It must have been exhausting to prepare enough for this many people. You have my sincere thanks.” Hayate’s eyes widened at the sight of all the dishes lining the table.

As a tax officer traveling through many different villages, he had been treated to numerous meals in each village chief’s home, but they rarely ever served meat so generously like this. His attendants were all buzzing happily, too.

“Rio is a very accomplished hunter. He’s quite multi-talented, and has been a huge help in our village.” Ruri praised Rio with pride.

“Oh? So Lord Rio not only prepared the food, but hunted the meat himself as well? While my party can hunt, when it comes to cooking, the most we can do is grill the meat and prepare simple campfire foods. Being able to do all this as a young man is most impressive.” Hayate praised Rio in awe along with Ruri. The “campfire foods” he spoke of were the food supplies they used during their field operations.

“I traveled alone for some time, so I picked up the skill naturally. I was in charge of the main dish, but Sayo made all the other side dishes. Please eat up before they cool,” Rio said, looking at Sayo, prompting all the male attendants to liven up.

“Ooh, a woman’s cooking!”

Sayo ducked her head in embarrassment. Rio smiled wryly, and Hayate scolded his aides in shame. “Quiet down, all of you. Now, we shall dig in immediately. You have my deepest gratitude for your exceptional hospitality.” Hayate cleared his throat and sat up straight.

Yuba took that as a sign. “Then, let us eat,” she said, and everyone began their meal.

“If I may so inquire, Lord Rio, what kind of meat dish is this? I can tell it some sort of avian meat, but I am not familiar with the scent. The aroma is most appetizing, I must say,” Hayate asked, having picked up a slice of the meat between his chopsticks and brought it to his nose to smell.

“This recipe is one that I acquired during my travels through foreign countries, which involved grilling the meat with herbs. The somewhat-unique aroma is characteristic to that recipe, but the main ingredient is the Lenou bird.”

“I see... The Lenou bird, hm? Ah, this is indeed... how shall I put this... delicious!”

Hayate swallowed his drool and placed the slice of meat in his mouth. The instant he bit down, the juicy flavor of the meat — with its perfectly complimentary seasoning — exploded in his mouth, making his eyes widen.

Seeing his reaction, the aides reached for the herb-grilled meat in a hurry, groaning in unison at the delicious taste on their tongues. They gobbled down their rice with it.

“How did you create such a wondrous taste?” Hayate asked with great interest.

“The main seasoning is salt and pepper, but I’ve also used some special herbs and oil that aren’t native to this area for flavor. The secret ingredient is a little bit of honey,” Rio explained.

“Ooh, you used pepper? Such a valuable ingredient... Was it really okay to use all these ingredients that are not native to our kingdom?” Hayate responded in surprise with a tinge of remorse.

“That’s all right. It’d be pointless to hold on to it forever, anyway. I decided to use it when I heard that an important guest was visiting the village.”

Salt was harvested in certain kingdoms with temperate climates across both the Yagumo and Strahl regions, so while it was pricey, it wasn’t impossible to obtain. While Rio had all the ingredients he could ever want preserved in the Time-Space Cache, he wasn’t foolish enough to openly reveal that, so he made up a lie that was suitable for the situation.

Well, that wasn’t the only reason. If he could use this opportunity to gain their guests’ favor, it might benefit the village if anything were to happen in the future. It appeared that everything was going exactly as Rio had planned, as Hayate seemed to be revising his evaluation of Rio in a positive way.

“Umm, is pepper an expensive ingredient?” Ruri asked, still unsure of the value of the item.

“Well, it’s not as big of a deal in the areas where it is produced, but it isn’t cheap to purchase in our kingdom. The last time I saw it in the markets of the capital, it went for ten times the price of salt,” Hayate replied thoughtfully.

“Huh?!”

“Fweh?!”

Ruri and Sayo’s eyes widened in shock. While Yuba hadn’t made any noise, her eyes had widened by a fraction, too.

Rio had used pepper in his dishes for Yuba and Ruri several times before, but he had never disclosed the value of the seasoning. It wasn’t the kind of item the villagers would have any interest in during their lifetimes, so it was only natural that Ruri and the others were unaware of its worth.

“Rio, have you been using something that expensive on us the whole time?! You should have said so!” Ruri yelled in flabbergasted shock.

“...Erm, didn’t I say I had a lot less pepper than salt?”

“Y-You may have mentioned that, but you never said it was so expensive! Ugh...”

“Umm, I purchased it in one of the production areas, so it wasn’t that expensive.”

“E-Even so. If it was such a valuable item, you could have kept it for yourself...”

“I said there was no point in holding onto it forever, didn’t I? Don’t worry about it, really. Come on, let’s eat dinner before it gets cold.” Rio shook his head with a wry smile.

Thus, they settled down and resumed their meal. Eventually, the village’s specialty brew was served, turning the scene into a lively commotion. By the time Rio and Sayo prepared additional side dishes for the drinks, the male attendants were already flushed red with liquor.

“You all are going to feel it tomorrow if you drink too much now,” Hayate, their superior, said with a sigh.

“Haha — we know, Sir Hayate,” the aides replied with a strained laugh.

At the moment, the conversation was split between Yuba and the male attendants in one group, and Rio, Ruri, Sayo, and Hayate in another group.

“Are you not going to have even a single cup, Lord Hayate?” Rio asked.

“It is not that I do not want to, it is simply that I try to refrain from drinking when out on a job,” Hayate replied stoically.

“I see,” Rio replied with admiration.

“Ruri and Sayo aside, why are you not drinking, Lord Rio? There is no need to hold back just because we are here.” Hayate asked Rio the same question.

“I have my daily training to do after this, so I’m practicing self-restraint for today.”

“Oh, so you are studying some form of martial arts. I had surmised as much from the way you held yourself.”

“Yes. It’s just a hobby, though.”

“Hahaha. There is no need to be modest about it. You have traveled around the world at such a young age — I am sure you have considerable skill. Would you tell me a few tales from your travels? I rarely ever have the chance to leave the kingdom and travel elsewhere myself,” Hayate said with a soft laugh.

“It may not be very interesting to you,” Rio warned him in advance, nodding.

Hayate went ahead and began to question Rio about his journey. Ruri and Sayo listened intently for the most part, occasionally interrupting with their own questions for Rio. He answered their questions with as much as he was comfortable revealing; eventually, they asked about his parents’ hometown, which he named as the Karasuki Kingdom.

“So, your parents were born in this country. Then, it’s possible that you were named after the person who appeared in the legends of our kingdom.” Hayate nodded in understanding.

“Aah, you mean the legend of Ryuo the Hero? That sure brings back memories. My father used to tell me about it,” Ruri said nostalgically, the story in question immediately coming to mind.

“Is it a famous story?” Rio cocked his head and asked Sayo, who sat beside him.

“Yes. All of the villagers hear about it when they’re children.” Sayo nodded.

“What kind of legend is it?”

“Let me see. If I recall correctly...” Hayate began to relay the story.

Once upon a time, over a thousand years ago (before the kingdom of Karasuki had been formed), evil beings ran rampant all over the land, threatening the livelihood of the people. They devastated the land, leaving a huge trail of death and despair in their wake. That was when the hero, who the people would later call Ryuo, appeared.

Ryuo was a strong, kind, and exceptional person. He was able to single-handedly take on and defeat the evil beings that the people of the time were helpless against. He shared his food with anyone on the brink of starving to death, and would heal anyone’s severe injuries in the blink of an eye.

It was said that he also taught spirit arts to the people of the Yagumo region, back when there were barely any users at all.

People from all over flocked to these lands to rely on Ryuo. They placed him on a pedestal as their hero, and it was only a matter of time before a new kingdom was established around them.

However, Ryuo was only one man, and there was a limit to what he could do alone.

No matter how many evil beings he defeated, they continued to spawn out of nowhere. At the same time, surges of poverty-stricken citizens that had heard the rumors came calling, seeking his salvation. Despite this, Ryuo continued fighting without rest, and continued to act as a savior without respite. He continued saving without rest. Because he was so strong and so kind, he alone remained the perfect hero for the people.

No matter how much he suffered, Ryuo maintained the image of a completely flawless hero... until a time where there were mass casualties.

One day, Ryuo declared that he had located the place where the evil beings were spawning from. His plan was to head there immediately in order to eliminate them, but no one else was capable of standing and fighting alongside him. So, accompanied by only one travel companion, Ryuo departed for the place where the evil beings originated from, leaving the people behind to wait for his return.

That was when tragedy occurred.

While Ryuo was away, hordes of evil beings ambushed the humans in full force. Those that faced the evil beings did so with their armies, but without Ryuo fighting alongside them, their death toll only continued to climb higher and higher. By the time Ryuo had returned, the lands were thoroughly ravaged by the war that had broken out in his absence.

Ryuo used his mighty strength to annihilate the advancing evil beings in an instant, but once the war was over, someone spoke up.

Why?

Why didn’t you come to save us sooner?

Why did you leave us here to die?

Although Ryuo apologized for his late arrival, someone else insisted:

The dead won’t return.

The dead won’t rest in peace just because you apologized.

Of course, it’s not like we haven’t had any casualties until now...

However, there had never been a single battle that brought about as many deaths as this one, and the people’s expectations had been betrayed. The discontent that had built up during the war amongst the people grew as a collective mass, and exploded all at once.

While there were some within that mass that tried to calm the others, there was no way for the voice of the few to reach through to the rioting mob.

Ryuo did not fulfill his duty as a hero — the people saw him guilty of that sin — but he bowed his head before them and accepted their criticisms at face value.

As a result, Ryuo declared himself unfit for the title of king, and renounced himself from the throne.

The new dynasty began shortly after — the antecedent to the current Kingdom of Karasuki.

Life continued peacefully henceforth, with no further attacks from the evil beings. Once an extended period of time had passed with no conflicts, the people finally realized that Ryuo had destroyed the origins of the evil beings, precisely as he said he would.

Thus, the people started pondering out loud in recollection. Where might Ryuo be at this moment? they wondered, but by that point, Ryuo had already disappeared from the land.

“The threat of evil beings attacking this land has diminished, but they still exist. I must eliminate the dangers that remain,” he had told a select few people before leaving the kingdom.

The king publicly announced the truth to the people: an admission that they had committed an unforgivable crime in driving Ryuo away, which prompted the people to reflect.

After time had passed, they would speak of the legends of Ryuo, passing his stories down from one generation to the next. They acknowledged their faults, and prayed that one day, their hero would return.

Once Hayate had finished his story, he let out a small sigh.

“I do not know if this folk tale truly happened or not. I do not even know if this Ryuo truly existed. However, I believe the story is one that should be passed on. There is much that can be learned from it,” he said.

“I always felt sorry for the king in that story and cried over him when I was little. It still makes me feel a little gloomy, even now,” Ruri murmured with a helpless smile.

“I think I cried the first time I heard it, too...” added Sayo. “But the Great Ryuo from the story sounds lovely.”

“His name really is similar to Rio’s, after all,” Ruri teased.

“T-That’s not the reason why!” Sayo said, blushing.

“Ahaha,” Ruri laughed. “But, if Rio’s parents really did name him after this story, I wonder what kind of meaning they wanted to put behind it. Did they want him to become someone like Ryuo?” Ruri said, pondering to herself.

“...Who knows?” Rio said with a soft, somewhat fond smile.

The four of them continued to chat for a while longer.

“Here you are, Sir Hayate. Please have some tea.” Ruri poured some tea and offered it to Hayate beside her.

“Ah, right. Thank you,” When Ruri’s body approached his, Hayate offered his gratitude. He took a sip of his tea before expressing his strong impression of the taste. “It is delicious.”

“You don’t need to exaggerate. It’s just the cheap stuff the villagers drink.”

“No, that is not true at all. Lady Ruri poured this tea. Your average tea cannot compare.”

“Ahaha. You flatter me.” Ruri perceived Hayate’s words as a compliment, and laughed in amusement.

What a fascinating person, Rio thought as he watched their antics with a smile.

While Hayate could be a bit blunt and awkward, he was an honest and genuine person. He was the 18-year-old heir to one of the kingdom’s advanced martial arts families. Despite wearing the mantle of his family lineage, he never used his position to domineer over others. He normally carried himself with dignity, but when it came to Ruri, his reactions seemed somewhat innocent and naive. Rio’s impression of Hayate was quite favorable.

On the other hand, Ruri was already a girl of marriageable age and favored highly by many of the male villagers. Even as her cousin, Rio found her to be charming. He hoped she would marry someone who didn’t have any baggage, but Ruri herself never brought it up, and therefore did not seem interested.

Along came Hayate — a young man with a highly promising future, who already seemed to have fallen for Ruri. Of course, while the final decision of marriage was ultimately up to the two of them, Hayate certainly had no shortcomings as a candidate to become Ruri’s husband.

With that thought, Rio nonchalantly struck up a conversation with Sayo beside him, hoping to give Ruri and Hayate the space to speak to each other alone. Sayo seemed to be thinking along the same lines as Rio, springing enthusiastically at the chance to talk to Rio.

Thus, time passed in the blink of an eye.

“If we chat any longer than this, we will all be exhausted come morning. Let us end the party now,” Hayate suggested. He had been thoroughly enjoying his conversation with Ruri, but at the same time, he knew when to back off.

“Yes, let’s. Sayo, you should stay over tonight. It’s already late, so you can sleep with me.” Ruri said, deciding that Sayo would sleep over; there was no need to inform Shin, as he already knew that there was a chance of this happening.

They quickly cleaned everything up and retired to their beds, with the exception of Rio, who went to complete his training practice.

◇◇◇

Rio swung his sword under the cover of night in the garden of the village chief’s house. His breaths came out harshly, his body emitting heat as a white steam rose from his skin. After attentively swinging his sword for several minutes, he took a deep breath and returned his sword to its sheath.

“Phew...”

It was already late into the night, so he decided to wrap up and immediately headed toward the bathhouse nearby. However...

“Hm?” Rio froze on the spot, feeling a presence hidden in the darkness.

He turned his eyes toward the direction of the presence; at the same time, he manipulated the wind with his spirit arts, blowing a light breeze in the same direction.

Wind-related spirit arts were also good for detecting essence, as a high level wind spirit arts user was capable of releasing wind embedded with a faint amount of their own essence. This tactic allowing the wind to detect the essence of anything it touched.

Rio couldn’t visually confirm someone’s figure due to the darkness, but he could detect the slight amount of essence coming from what was most likely a person walking down the road in front of the village chief’s house.

Is someone walking around at this time?

It was late enough for most villagers to be asleep already, but not late enough to say there couldn’t possibly be anyone out and about at this time.

There was only one essence reaction, and its owner was getting further and further from the village chief’s home.

...Well, whatever.

If it wasn’t getting any closer, then there was no need to pay it any more attention. Rio picked up the towel he left next to him and wiped his sweat away.

With Gon’s group of outsiders staying in the village, Rio had secretly set up sorcery barriers yesterday that could detect intruders around the village chief’s house. If anyone entered the grounds, he would know immediately. Specifically, if a living being with a certain amount of essence crossed the barrier, the spirit stone being used as the source of essence for the barrier would react by giving off a huge amount of light and heat. The efficacy of the barrier could be toggled at will, and the barrier would fail to activate if the spirit stone was carried outside of the barrier.

Since many people were always going in and out during the day, Rio kept the barrier off during the daylight hours and activated its effect at night.

At the moment, the spirit stone core of the barrier was silent.

After Rio washed the sweat from his body and cleaned himself in the bath, he retired to his room and fell asleep.

◇◇◇

Not long after Rio fell asleep, in a small cabin on the outskirts of the village...

“Let’s get going,” Gon said in an impatient tone.

About an hour ago, he had sent one of his underlings to scope out the village chief’s house in advance. The underling had reported hearing someone in the garden, so they had waited on standby until now.

Thanks to that, restlessness was pent up within him. Unable to withstand those hasty feelings any longer, Gon jumped to his feet and left the cabin with several other men.

Although their vision was impaired by the darkness, they quietly and carefully made their way to the village chief’s house. Not a single villager was awake at this time of night, making silence dominate the air surrounding the village.

When they arrived before the village chief’s house, with practiced movements, Gon made his way around the side of the house and removed the wooden sliding window attached to the side of a particular room. He had visited Yuba’s house numerous times before while accompanying his parents, so he knew where Ruri’s room was located. He also knew that the sliding door was the easiest point of entry.

The wooden sliding door was supported by a stick on the inside, but that stick had no effect if the entire door was removed, though there was nothing he could do about the moderately-loud clunking sound that it made.

Gon handed the removed sliding door to one of his followers and swiftly snuck into the room. Barely a minute had passed since they entered the property.

Hm? There’s two of them?

He froze at the sight of two girls sleeping on two mats spread out before him.

Tch, why are there two of them? Ruri and... Who’s this? I’ve seen this face somewh— Ooh, it’s Shin’s sister!

The unexpected turn of events made Gon click his tongue. He approached the two figures to get a better look at their faces in the dark. He immediately identified one of them as his target, Ruri, and belatedly realized that the other one was Sayo. A wide grin spread across Gon’s face.

“Mm... Is someone there?” Ruri stirred from where she lay next to Sayo. She had probably been awakened by the sounds from before, and the presence of someone in the room.

“Tch,” Gon clicked his tongue again. He leaned over her body and smothered her mouth.

“Mmgh?!”

Naturally, that anomaly made Ruri’s eyes snap open.

“Quiet. If you make a fuss, I’ll make you regret it,” Gon threatened right in Ruri’s face. With those words, she realized who the intruder was.

Gon.

“Mmm! Mm, mmrgh!” Unwilling to yield to Gon’s demand, Ruri started to kick and struggle.

“Hey, I told you not to move—” Gon tried to threaten her further, but this time, Sayo woke up.

“...Ruri? Huh? U-Umm, wha—”

Shit— With that spur-of-the-moment thought, Gon brought his fist down next to Ruri’s pinned face with great force. Thump. It made a blunt noise that echoed, making Ruri and Sayo flinch with their entire bodies.

“Listen up!”

Gon spoke to them in a quiet but intimidating whisper. He grabbed Ruri by the collar and swung his fist at her face, stopping moments before it made contact.

“If you keep fussing, the next one goes to your face. Got it?” he continued.

Overwhelmed by his intensity, Ruri stopped resisting.

“Hmph,” Gon huffed in satisfaction. “And that goes for you, too,” he said, grabbing Sayo closer by the collar.

“A-Ah... Uh...”

“Do you hear me? Nod your heads.” The violent approach had Sayo in tears as Gon continued to pressure them menacingly. Sayo almost reflexively nodded her head, but...

“W-Wha— You— Gah?!”

The yells of one of Gon’s followers could be heard from outside the sliding door. At the same time, the sound of something heavy being thrown rang out.

“What is happening, Lord Rio?! Wha— You there, what do you think you are doing?!”

Hayate’s voice could be heard further away, which meant that the one who defeated Gon’s follower just now was probably Rio. He had detected an abnormality in the spirit stone core of the sorcery barrier and came running.

“Shit, we gotta run!” the voices of the men outside were saying. Everything had become noisy all at once.

“Hold it! You will not escape!”

Hayate chased after the man who fled into the night.

“Fuck, they found us! How— Gwah?!” Gon was visibly aggravated at the turn of events, when a dazzling light shone into the room from outside, making everything before him turn to a pure white.

Rio had blinded Gon’s vision, having stuck his left hand out and shone a light into the room with spirit arts. Once he saw the sight of Gon clutching Sayo by the collar and Ruri’s disorderly clothes, he spoke to Gon in an icy cold voice.

“...What are you doing?” he asked.

“Kuh, fuck you!” Gon hurriedly released his grip on Sayo’s collar and broke into a run toward the door outside. He intended on forcibly knocking Rio away from where he stood before the doorway, but...

“Gah! Hah?!”

Rio easily sent him flying, his back hitting the ground with a loud slam. He didn’t even have time to brace himself for the landing, placing a huge amount of pressure on his chest and knocking the breath out of his lungs.

“...Why are you running? I asked what you were doing. Answer me.”

Rio’s face was completely void of expression as he looked down at Gon, who was gasping for breath. “Hah... Hah... Hh...”

“What’s wrong? Answer me. What were you trying to do?”

“Hahn... Hh...” Gon wheezed through his mouth, desperately seeking oxygen.

“Oi, hurry up and answer me. You want to breathe, don’t you?” Rio roughly grabbed Gon by the collar. Tightening his grip around his neck, Rio intentionally made it even harder for Gon to breathe.

“Hah... Ahh... Night... crawling... R-Rape...”

In a desperate attempt to be saved, Gon unthinkingly gasped out the words “night crawling” and “rape.” His voice was so strained, it was difficult to make out the sounds clearly, but that hardly mattered. Rio knew the answer before he even asked.

“Oh, really.” He nodded noncommittally, then swung at Gon’s face with all his strength.

“Gah! Agh!” Gon groaned in pain.

“...I’m not done yet.” Rio’s fist drove into Gon’s face once more.

He didn’t hesitate for a moment; there was even some killing intent behind his punch. It was hard to believe these were the actions of someone who once felt a sense of reluctance about killing someone who had tried to kill him first. The moment Rio laid his eyes on the scene of Gon assaulting both Ruri and Sayo, his head was filled with a flashback of the last time he saw his mother.

He would never forget it.

The sight of Ayame being toyed with by men in order to protect her powerless 5-year-old son...

Before he knew it, Rio was taking out his emotions on Gon, his body moving of its own accord.

There was no holding back the endless hatred flowing out of him. Something had snapped inside of him — he had completely lost his mind.

“...Ah, ah, ah...”

Gon pleaded for his life through wheezing gasps, but Rio didn’t let up on his punches for even a second.

He wouldn’t let him fall unconscious.

He wouldn’t give him an easy death.

He would never forgive him, no matter what.

Only after hurting him to the limits of pain that his body could endure would he kill him.

Chapter 8: An Unexpected Visitor

On a day after winter had arrived, when the villagers were holed up inside from the cold, Gouki visited the village without warning.

His business had to do with inviting Rio to visit Homura and Shizuku in the castle once more, so Rio departed for the capital again. It had been several months since they last met, but there was none of the nerves from last time as Rio calmly took part in the secret meeting.

“I’m sorry for calling you here so suddenly, in the cold,” Homura said after they exchanged some simple greetings and took their seats.

“No, there’s no work to be done in the village during winter to begin with.”

“Come to think of it, the last time we met, it was the fall season. We actually wanted to meet you a little earlier, but there was still much business we wanted to finish tending to first.” Being unable to meet their grandson when they wanted to was saddening — Homura sighed as though to say just that.

“Thank you for taking the opportunity to meet me during such a busy time.”

“No, it’s fine. Besides, we had something important we wanted to discuss this time.” Homura looked at him with a somewhat questioning look.

“Something important?” Rio asked, adjusting his posture.

“Yes. It has to do with you getting your revenge,” Homura said quietly.

“What would you like to discuss?” Rio questioned with a slightly stiff expression.

“Hm. First of all, I detest Lucius too. Emotionally, I wish for nothing more than to assist you... But, as the king, I unfortunately cannot leave this kingdom.”

“I believe that was to be expected...”

“...And that is why I thought of preparing a small number of retainers to gift you. They will lend you their strength on behalf of Shizuku and I. Won’t you use them as needed?”

“Huh... Eh?” The bombshell Homura dropped took Rio by surprise, making him freeze on the spot.

“What do you say?” Homura asked again, warmly watching over Rio’s dumbfounded surprise.

“U-Umm, no, I couldn’t possibly...” Rio expressed signs of his disapproval, but Homura wasn’t about to back down just like that.

“I plan on assigning you a dozen or so retainers. They will be led by Gouki and Kayoko.”

“...And did the others agree to the two of them?” Rio nearly felt like clutching his head in his hands, but he endured it with his mind of steel and voiced his question, looking over at Gouki and Kayoko within the room.

“Naturally,” Homura confirmed. Gouki and Kayoko also vigorously nodded their heads, and Rio finally realized that Homura and Shizuku were serious.

“If someone as great as Lord Gouki disappeared from this kingdom, I believe the repercussions would be significant, to say the least...” Rio addressed the main issue in a roundabout way.

Gouki was renowned for being the greatest warrior of the Karasuki Kingdom. His strength was on par with an army of a thousand, and he had garnered great results and trust from the kingdom. For Gouki to abandon that and disappear without a trace, there would no doubt be an uproar within the kingdom.

“Worry not. The necessary arrangements regarding that have already been made — it’s the basics of politics.”

“...Is that so.”

Rio found himself at a loss for words, having been told so confidently that there was no problem. It was clear that they had considered their words carefully, so if he spoke without rationally forming his argument, he might end up sealing the deal.

“However, Lord Gouki has his family, not to mention the history of the Saga family and their public duties. What shall become of those?” Rio reasoned as he began his rebuttal.

“That is not an issue. The only ones to become your retainers from the Saga family are Gouki and Kayoko. Although, Komomo did say she will come along too, her being a retainer or not aside,” Homura said, glancing at Gouki and Kayoko.

“Yes. We will be bringing Komomo along, but my son and all the others will remain in this land. Thus, it shall not impede the continuance of the Saga family in this kingdom,” Gouki said in an unwavering tone.

“My destination — the Strahl region — isn’t a journey that can be so easily returned from. Lord Gouki alone may take several months to make the trip. There is a possibility you may not meet your family again.”

“As a warrior, one must always be prepared for the possibility of never seeing their family again when they venture onto the battlefield. This is no different,” Gouki said.

It was difficult to rationally argue against such views of life when brought up so instantaneously.

“No, but that isn’t the issue... How will you explain this to Lord Hayate and the others?”

“Though it may have been presumptuous of us, we have already explained everything to my son. Everyone has accepted it.”

“And that applies to the others accompanying us, too? Wouldn’t some of them feel reluctant to leave the kingdom?”

“Due to various circumstances, the others are all members of the undercover squad associated with my family. They have no kin, are devoted, and are all extremely skilled, so they shall not be a hindrance.”

“...However, there is no proof that that man — that Lucius is even alive,” Rio said, trying to convince Gouki not to accompany him.

“Sir Rio, this is an opportunity that we have yearned for for a long time. While our hatred for Lucius plays a large part of it, this is a once in a lifetime chance for Kayoko and I to fulfill the dearest wish we were unable to accomplish in the past. So, please, I beg this of you,” Gouki implored, bowing his head deeply at Rio.

With that, Rio finally understood. Gouki and the others weren’t coming along because they were ordered to, they were coming along because they wanted to. His clumsy logical arguments weren’t going to be enough to make them back down. But, even then, Rio had no intention of making Gouki and the others his retainers. It wasn’t a matter of logic — he just didn’t think he was strong enough to bear the weight of the lives of others. Which was why...

“I cannot accept your assistance. I appreciate the thought, but this is something I must do myself.” Rio could only reject Gouki and the others’ intentions.

“I see. So, it has come to this after all...” Homura groaned bitterly. It seemed he had predicted Rio’s refusal from the beginning. Gouki and the others didn’t seem to be too shaken, either.

“Rio... We hate Lucius just as you do, and we cannot rest easy until he bears responsibility. As we feel the same as you, we cannot allow you to shoulder all the burden of revenge by yourself,” Homura said hesitantly to Rio.

“That is... Even so — no. Furthermore, it is not that I wish to look down upon you, but Lord Gouki and the others wouldn’t be able to keep up with me.” Rio shook his head firmly.

“What... do you mean? The party consists of the finest warriors in my kingdom. I find it hard to believe that they will not be able to keep up...”

“This is what I mean...”

It’d be faster to just show them; they would have no choice but to back down at the utter gap in their abilities. With that thought, Rio willingly revealed one of the tricks he had up his sleeve.

As he spoke those last few words, Rio used his wind spirit arts. A breeze stirred in the room, lifting Rio’s body into the air. Homura and the others widened their eyes in mute amazement.

“Wha... A-Are you floating?”

“It’s not simply floating. I can move by flying through the air. And so, you won’t be able to keep up with me just by enhancing your physical body with spirit arts, since I can fly right over any obstacles.”

The hand that Rio revealed was incredibly effective; Homura and the others listened to Rio’s commentary in awe.

“...To think that wind spirit arts could be used in such a way... Gouki, you specialize in wind spirit arts. Can you do the same?” Homura asked. Gouki’s face twisted in frustration.

“...I cannot,” he replied.

So, this was the gimmick behind the extraordinary speed he showed during the sparring match. I see... Gouki realized with chagrin.

If it was just using wind to push his body from behind, then Gouki was capable of it, too, but he couldn’t use it in a real combat situation. If he made any sort of error in output force or direction, it would have conversely placed him in even greater trouble.

“Can you think of anyone else who can do this?”

“...No, I cannot. I myself am capable of creating a gust of wind and sending myself through he air, but when it comes to floating in the air with such stability...”

“Is that so... I understand. Rio, we will back down for now. But, please, would you keep this offer in the back of your head? You may change your mind before you depart.”

“...I understand.”

Though he doubted that would happen, Rio agreed.

◇◇◇

The day after he declined the gift of retainers from Homura, Rio was staying at the Saga residence, just like the last time he was in the capital. There, Komomo had badgered him until he agreed to join her in training practice. Once their training had lulled, Komomo suddenly asked him a question.

“Will you be heading toward the far western lands, Sir Rio?”

“Yes, that’s right,” Rio nodded.

“Umm! I wish to accompany you, Sir Rio!” Komomo proposed without a moment’s delay. Her face had an expression of true purity as she looked up at Rio with a cheerful grin.

“...You can’t.”

Komomo’s puppy eyes held a charm that caused any person, regardless of gender, to fall for her demands, but Rio somehow managed to resist them.

“I can’t... no matter what?”

“No matter what.” Rio shook his head curtly.

“Aww...” Komomo puff her cheeks in a pout.

“Lord Gouki, please refrain from using your daughter as a means of temptation,” Rio raised as an objection, seeing straight through the instigator behind her. He turned to give an exasperated look to Gouki, who was watching the training take place from beside them.

“Hum, it seems I’ve been seen through.”

“Obviously. Even for Komomo, the journey would be far too harsh for a ten-year-old girl, you realize? Please, don’t be absurd.”

While there had been a precedent before, Rio chose not to mention Latifa.

“But Komomo has acquired the ability to enhance herself through spirit arts. The long road would be a good learning experience for her.”

“No, it’s not meant to be a learning experience...”

While the long and harsh journey may indeed be a good learning experience, the muscle-headed optimism of treating it as a training opportunity made Rio sigh. The fact that Komomo herself was ready and rearing to go left him at even more of a loss.

“At any rate, the only one who will be heading to the Strahl region is me.”

“...That is true. The earlier meeting showed just how resolute you are. If you are adamant that it is impossible, then we mustn’t insist on accompanying you anymore.” Gouki smiled wryly with a small shrug.

“Huh? Uh, right...” Rio was taken aback at how easily Gouki gave up. To be honest, he had expected a bit more resistance, which was why he couldn’t help but send an examining look Gouki’s way.

“Hm, what is the matter?”

“Ah, no. If Lord Gouki is fine with that, then I have no particular objections...” Fearing causing more trouble for himself, Rio refrained from asking any further.

“But it is a little lonely. We don’t have very many opportunities to meet you to begin with, so to think of you leaving for somewhere far away is... You’ll be returning to the village in a few days, yes?” Komomo hung her head as she expressed her feelings.

“Yes. Unfortunately, that is the case.” Rio nodded with a troubled expression.

“Then, when does that mean we can meet again?”

“Let’s see... That would depend on the availability of His and Her Majesty, but I believe the earliest would be next month...”

“After next month...” Komomo became even more gloomy.

“Komomo...” Rio looked down at Komomo with a conflicted expression.

“I... I wish to go to Sir Rio’s village,” Komomo whispered, looking up at Rio’s face.

“To... my village?”

“Yes. I wish to remain by your side. I’d like to have you train me more, and I want to know what the village you are living in is like.” Unable to hold back her tenacity, Komomo spilled all her desires.

While he couldn’t permit her to follow him to the Strahl region, if it was only as far as the village, then Rio didn’t mind at all.

“Well, there shouldn’t be an issue as long as Lord Gouki and Yuba permit it...” Rio muttered.

“...Hm. There are no objections on my side. I haven’t allowed her outside much ever since the kidnapping attempt, so it may be a good change of pace.” Gouki began to consider it optimistically.

“Huh? Can I really?”

“I do not mind. While I am not so sure about other villages, this is the village that Sir Rio is living in. Hmm... For now, I shall pen a letter to Yuba and discuss it with her,” Gouki said enthusiastically, walking from the training grounds toward the mansion to begin his aforementioned task.

“...I can go to Sir Rio’s village?!” Komomo asked Rio in delight.

“N-Not yet, it hasn’t been finalized...” Rio faltered and shook his head.

Was I a bit too hasty? he reassessed, but it was a little too late to wonder.

After that, arrangements were made in a flurry, and Komomo’s stay in the village was decided; it was for an extended period of time, along with her caretaker, Aoi. And as long as they had the time to do so, there was the added bonus of Gouki, Kayoko, and Hayate occasionally coming to visit.

Rio had a hunch that winter was about to get quite busy.

◇◇◇

Several weeks later, Rio was walking through the village, showing Komomo around.

“It’s like a dream... Being able to come to Sir Rio’s village like this. The scenery is beautiful and the air is clear — I think it’s a wonderful place,” Komomo said with great delight.

“The capital is brimming with people, after all. You can’t enjoy this kind of scenery very often. I’m glad you find it to your liking, Komomo,” Rio replied with a slightly strained smile.

The sounds of insects could be heard echoing around him, and the plants rustled in the wind to form a symphony with the sound of the movement of Rio’s sword. It was such a pleasant feeling that he almost wanted to keep training forever — but with dinner waiting for him, Rio finished revising his sword movements and moved onto his body formation next.

Around ten minutes of moving his body later, Rio came to a sudden stop.

“This isn’t interesting to watch, is it?” he called out with a wry smile to Ruri and Sayo, who were standing by the doorway and silently watching on. Sayo’s body flinched.

“Ahaha, so you noticed us after all? Is that what they call martial arts? Your movements were so graceful, I couldn’t help but watch,” Ruri said, giving a carefree smile.

“It’s just my daily training,” Rio replied with a strained smile.

“No, no, it’s really impressive. I can’t believe you can keep at it without getting bored. You’ve done it every day since you came here,” Ruri said with earnest admiration.

“Huh? You do this every day?” Sayo’s eyes widened in surprise.

For the record, she was here because she felt too awkward to go home and face Shin after their earlier squabble, so Ruri forcefully dragged her with them. Rio had briefly wondered about what Shin would eat for dinner, but Sayo reassured him there were leftovers from breakfast.

“Yup, he does this at least once a day around this time. Amazing, right?” Ruri gave a small shrug.

“Yes, it’s amazing...”

“By the way, I’ve always wanted to ask. Why did you start learning martial arts, Rio?” Ruri suddenly brought up her question, figuring it was a good opportunity to do so.

“Why, you ask?”

“Yeah. I don’t really understand martial arts, but even to my amateur eye, I can tell your training is impressive. Not everyone can put in the amount of effort to reach that level.”

“Let’s see... It’s a little embarrassing to say since it’s so simple, but I think any young boy would have the same reason,” Rio replied with a grin, having carefully considered his answer.

“Eeeh, what’s with that?! I’m so curious! Don’t you wanna know, too, Sayo?”

“Y-Yeah. I want to hear more.”

Ruri and Sayo were both brimming with curiosity.

“Ahaha... What to do. May I put on my clothes first?” Rio gave a wry smile before picking up his towel and clothes he had left to the side.

“Huh? Ah, yeah. Sorry, sorry. Go ahead,” Ruri replied a bit shyly, though she hadn’t really cared since they were both cloaked in the darkness of the night.

Sayo only noticed after Rio’s comment, too, making her suddenly flush red and look down. Rio took that chance to quickly wipe his sweat off and throw a shirt on.

“All right, now that you’ve got your clothes on, tell us already! Why did you start learning martial arts?” Ruri pressed for an answer. Having calmed down, Sayo approached Rio to make sure she didn’t miss anything.

Rio gave in to their demands, and began to tell his story. “It’s just from when I was a child, okay?” he said, as though he were ashamed.

“Back then, there was a girl I liked... I wanted to become stronger so I could protect her.”

“...Huh. You had a girl you liked, Rio? That’s kind of unexpected. Wait, does that mean you don’t like that girl anymore?” Ruri asked with wide eyes.

“...It doesn’t mean I hate her or anything, it’s just that we’re estranged. She might have a lover already, or she may not even remember me...” Rio spoke with a smile and a small huff of laughter, but his gaze seemed distant.

“Sir Rio, you worked so hard for that girl... Won’t you have a chance to meet her again?” Sayo asked timidly, looking closely at Rio’s expression.

“I don’t even know where she is. The last time we met was a long time ago.” Rio shook his head slowly.

“But, if she’s alive, you may meet her again someday, Rio. All your efforts might pay off,” Ruri said in a bright voice, wanting to uplift the gloomy atmosphere.

“...You’re right. And, well... Now I’m training for my own sake.” Rio nodded and gave a vague smile.

Ruri and Sayo looked at each other. “Really?” They asked together.

“Yes. It’s partly because I’m scared of losing something I’ve spent years cultivating, but I also need to be strong in order to travel alone. You can only fight the unreasonable with raw power itself.” Rio lightly formed a fist, speaking in a stiff voice.

“Is it really that dangerous? Traveling alone...” Sayo asked hesitantly, noticing the air around Rio tensing up.

“Yes. There are dangerous animals and dangerous people.” Rio seemed to be aware of how he had stiffened up, and answered with a softer tone to his voice this time.

“That’s... true...” Sayo nodded weakly.

In this world, a person’s life was a fragile thing. People died from illness and famine. People died from war. People even died from being attacked by wild animals and bandits.

That was why it wouldn’t be strange for Rio to be attacked during his journey alone, and it wouldn’t be strange for him to defend himself by killing them. That was the first thought that came to Sayo’s mind.

However, she was too scared to know the truth, so she didn’t ask any more than that.

“Sorry for talking for so long. You two must be cold. Shall we head inside?” Rio changed the subject, making a suggestion with a bitter smile.

“Yeah, let’s. I came to call you because dinner was done, but I completely forgot about it.” Ruri agreed with a laugh. Sayo also smiled, giggling.

“Oh, that’s right. Do you want to bathe together after dinner, Sayo? In the bathtub Rio built. You still haven’t tried it, right?” Ruri offered.

“Can I really? It was only just built recently, so the wait list was really long...”

The small bathhouse Rio had constructed was currently the talk of the town, with many villagers all wanting to try it. As a result, a wait list had been formed.

“It’s fine, it’s fine. We lend it out to whoever wants to use it, but it’s still our bathtub in the end. Residents of the house and their guests can enter it at any time,” Ruri said smugly.

“Okay... Then — yes, please. Thank you very much, too, Sir Rio.” Sayo had been a little hesitant about receiving any kind of favorable treatment, but she lost to the temptation of the bathtub and ultimately nodded. She bowed her head at Rio and Sayo.

“All right, it’s decided! So, please make us some hot water later, Rio!” Ruri clapped her hands together in request.

There was a bath heater installed in the bathhouse to heat the water for the bathtub, but it was much faster to have Rio make the hot water with his spirit arts. And, more importantly, it didn’t use up any firewood.

“Sure thing. Leave it to me,” Rio said, nodding willingly.

“Ehehe, thank you! You can peep at Sayo when she’s changing as a thank you,” Ruri said teasingly.

“R-Ruri!” Sayo yelled with a bright red face.

“Ahaha, it’s just a joke!” Ruri said, retreating while she laughed.

Sayo made eye contact with Rio right beside her. “Geez! ...Ah, Sir Rio, please don’t peep at me, okay?” She pleaded in embarrassment.

“Of course I won’t,” Rio answered immediately, ever the gentleman.

...But if it was Rio, a little peek would be okay, Sayo thought.

Her cheeks immediately flushed right after — her heart seemed to be in a bit of turmoil.

That was the only thing in Rio’s mind as he moved his fist with just the right amount of control. He couldn’t see anything else around himself, but his rage that bordered on insanity engulfed those watching on.

Ruri’s body simply trembled, whereas Sayo cried for Rio to stop. Hayate stood stock still in a daze.

“What’s going on?!” Awakened by the commotion, Yuba and Hayate’s aides came running out of the front door with torches in hand. Thanks to that, Hayate finally snapped out of his stupor.

“N-No! Enough, Lord Rio! He will die if you hit him any more!” he said, trying to stop Rio in a panic.

He’ll die?

Of course he would, Rio was trying to kill him, after all. Spurred on by Hayate’s words, Rio straddled Gon’s body and moved to punch him even more, but Hayate grabbed Rio’s fist before it made contact. He glanced at Ruri and Sayo huddling together.

“Wait, Lord Rio! I understand how you feel, but you are frightening the girls. This man will face retribution in due time, but we must hear his testimony too. So, please. Won’t you stay your hand?” he pleaded strongly.

Rio finally came to his senses and looked at the two inside the room. His eyes made contact with Ruri, who immediately turned her face away, while Sayo was looking at Rio with terrible sadness in her eyes. That was when Rio finally let his fist fall limp.

Still, an indescribable rage continued to swirl around inside his chest. He couldn’t bear to look at Gon’s face any longer, otherwise he really would kill him.

“Gah... Hah... Hah...”

Rio let go of Gon’s collar and slammed the back of his head against the ground — hard. Gon’s face was so swollen already that he couldn’t feel any more pain from the impact. His breath came out in ragged gasps, and it was difficult to tell whether he was still conscious or not.

Rio let out a heavy sigh filled with all his irritation toward Gon; he didn’t feel even a shred of guilt looking at his state. He calmly wondered if he was such a cold-hearted person, as if he were a third-party spectator looking in on the situation.

“Is that... Gon?” Yuba approached fearfully, hovering the torch in her hand over to clearly reveal Gon’s face.

“Yes. He was caught red-handed trying to assault Lady Ruri and Lady Sayo. Please take care of them.”

Hayate gave Yuba a brief explanation before directing her toward the girls.

“...I understand.” Yuba nodded with a solemn expression and went over to the girls inside the room.

“All of you, split up. One group will go and apprehend the accomplices that have been knocked out outside, while the other group will head to the cabin where their fellow travelers are staying and investigate the situation there,” Hayate directed his attendants, who nodded and swiftly followed their orders.

Next, Hayate began to cast a healing spirit art on Gon’s wounded face. He summoned a faint healing light in his hand and brought it close to Gon’s face. The rate of recovery was clearly slow, though; Hayate perhaps did not specialize in healing spirit arts, or he could have been weakening the healing effect on purpose. Rio was capable of performing a much stronger level of healing spirit art, but he chose to stand there and watch in silence.

Eventually, Gon recovered up to a certain point, and groaned. “Uh, uugh...”

“Hey, are you awake?” Hayate said to Gon.

“I-It... Ith hur... hurths... Help... me...” Gon was moving his mouth desperately.

“...Lord Hayate. Allow me to handle the healing. I specialize in healing spirit arts, so I can heal him until he can speak properly.”

No one knew what Rio was thinking as he made such an offer to Hayate. Without waiting for Hayate’s agreement, he came right up to them and placed a hand against Gon’s face to cast the spirit art.

“Oh... This is...” Hayate muttered, seeing the swelling on Gon’s face fade away.

For a moment, he feared Rio would kill Gon on the spot, but seeing the healing being carried out exactly as stated made him give Rio the benefit of the doubt. Roughly ten seconds passed until Gon’s face had recovered enough for him to open his eyes. Rio stopped his healing spirit arts and gave Gon a direct order.

“Hey, wake up. You can speak now, right?”

“E-Eek! You!” Gon peeled open his swollen eyes, only to spot Rio’s face and react in shock. He tried to gather his strength and yell, but the pain made his face pull into a tight grimace.

“Watch how you speak. Who do you think healed you? Do you want me to undo what I just did?” Rio said coldly, making Gon gulp in pure fear. His hostility toward Rio had completely quieted and his gaze wandered in search of help.

“Lord Rio...” Unable to meet Gon’s eyes, Hayate called Rio’s name.

“Lord Hayate. How will this be dealt with?” Rio inquired with a cold voice.

“...Though it was unsuccessful, attempted rape is still a felony. He was caught in the act with myself, a government official, as witness. No one would complain if he was cut down right here and now. Or, you could seek punishment from the kingdom, in which case he would either be sentenced to the death penalty, or forced into penal slavery. He does have ties to this village, though, so the final decision is up to the affected parties or Lady Yuba,” Hayate replied, looking at Ruri and Sayo.

“Is that so...” Rio responded with a frown, but immediately took on the emotionless mask on his face as he looked down at Gon with an icy glare.

“That’s how it is. You’ll behave until everything is settled, won’t you?”

“Eek...” Gon trembled with a start.

“Answer me.”

“I-I got it! Ah, n-no, I understand! I’ll behave!” Rio’s faint irritation made Gon answer in fear.

It seems like the hypnosis is working. Rio turned an examining gaze toward Gon.

He had cast a spirit art of hypnosis on Gon as he was healing him before. While the effects of hypnosis arts weren’t permanent, they were often used for immoral purposes, so the spirit folk village had treated them as forbidden arts, depending on the intention of the use and the matter of the suggestion.

This time, the hypnosis Rio had cast leaned toward those forbidden arts. He had planted the suggestion that Gon should fear him.

Rio had never cast any hypnosis arts until now, but he didn’t hesitate to use it on Gon. Even if it went against his own morals, he wanted to thoroughly crush Gon’s mind.

Gon had taken a severe beating at Rio’s hands already, so the effects of the hypnosis took hold easily. It was even possible for the effects to linger after the hypnosis wore off.

Rio’s face twisted with a sour expression as he tore his gaze away from Gon. Then, he looked around at everyone standing and offered a word of apology.

“...Please accept my deepest apologies for losing my composure so dreadfully. It must have been quite unsightly, especially for Ruri and Sayo...”

“N-No, not at all. It’s all right.”

“T-Thank you very much, Sir Rio!”

Ruri shook her head hesitantly while Sayo thanked Rio in a shrill voice.

“...No, I have done nothing to be thanked for. I did something that hurt you two even more than you were already.”

“It’s okay, Rio. We’re fine, really...” Ruri answered worriedly because of the regretful expression on Rio’s face. She really wanted to ask how he was doing himself, but for some reason, she felt as though she shouldn’t.

“Sorry, I’m feeling a little tired. May I leave the rest to you?” Rio averted his gaze from Ruri and Sayo guiltily, turning toward Yuba and Hayate instead. He felt as though he shouldn’t remain at the scene any longer.

“Sure, we can talk properly later. Leave this to us for now. Thank you.” Yuba nodded with a gentle smile. Hayate also met Rio’s eyes and nodded with force.

“...Thank you very much. Then, if you’d please excuse me.” With those words, Rio turned on his heel. He went around to the front and entered the house.

“Ah...” Sayo was about to follow after Rio when Ruri’s hand stopped her. Her shoulders slumped as she wondered in a daze if it was really okay to leave things like this, but Ruri simply shook her head. There was no way to know the answer to that.

Rio returned to his room and lay on his sleeping mat, looking up at the ceiling. His face twisted on the verge of tears as he reflected on himself and how shameful his actions really were.

After behaving so violently — as though he had been the victim — and making the scene more chaotic, then scaring Ruri and Sayo, he was the first to run away.

He probably had a terrible image now, having made them accommodate his needs. In the end, he had most likely caused a huge amount of trouble.

“How pathetic,” Rio muttered to himself, then gritted his teeth and came to a decision.

Tomorrow would be the start of a new day. He might never return to his old self, but he would endeavor toward doing just that — on the outside, at least. That way, they would be able to return to those peaceful days once more.

For the whole night, Rio remained curled up on his futon, body trembling from his self-loathing.

“As soon as the security guards get here, I’ll let them escort him to the internment center and make him confess who he was working for.”

“I see... Well, it seems like the guards have just arrived.” As the two spoke, guards that had heard the commotion came running.

Rio heard them asking what had happened and looked at them, which drew the woman’s attention to them.

“Over here!” she yelled.

Rio took that chance to approach Sayo. “Let’s go, Sayo,” he said, taking her by the hand and pulling her along as he started to walk off.

“Eh? Ah, but... Are you sure?”

“Yes. I’d like to stay out of any trouble, if possible,” Rio said with a bitter smile at Sayo’s confusion.

“Ah, wait! Hold on!” The woman whose name he didn’t know called out in a fluster from behind him as she realized they were leaving. However, Rio took Sayo and promptly disappeared into the crowd of people.

After that, they somehow managed to finish their shopping by evening, and returned to their lodgings. Once they went inside, the women of the squad immediately took notice of the hairpin in Sayo’s hair, then hounded Sayo with questions, until she turned bright red, as she usually did.

Rio managed to get away before he got involved by pretending to talk about the day’s sales with the other men. The sales were going well, and they expected to depart for the village within a few days.

That estimation was on the mark, as Rio and the others left for the village several days later. Thus, their trades at the capital ended safely, and their journey back to the village proceeded without incident.

◇◇◇

Just as Rio and the others arrived back at the village, Hayate had also finished his duties and returned to the capital. After storing the land tax in the royal castle’s storehouses, he went straight home to the Saga family’s mansion.

As he went through the gates of his family home, the retainers of his house came out to greet him. The head of the Saga family — his father, Gouki — had ordered him to see him immediately upon his return. Hayate had intended on doing so anyway in order to greet him upon his return. However, he noticed the air around the family retainers was rather tense.

“Did something happen?” he asked one of them. Once he had been told that his little sister, Komomo, had nearly been kidnapped, he hurried to Gouki’s room without bothering to change.

“Excuse me, father. It is Hayate. I have just returned home.”

“Hm... Enter. Have you heard yet?” Gouki granted Hayate permission to enter his room, then immediately cut to the chase once they were facing each other.

“Yes — that Komomo was nearly kidnapped.”

“They got us good. Aiming for the only day of the month Komomo secretly goes to the market for field study,” Gouki uttered, vexed.

“Are you saying that the crime was planned in advance?” Hayate questioned.

“Indeed. The apprehended perpetrator confessed. Apparently, one of the servants in our house leaked the information. I’ve an idea regarding the mastermind behind it, but I lack proof. So, I’ve decided to conduct a sting operation to capture the servant. We should get results immediately,” Gouki reported on the situation indifferently, letting a cold and dark smile peek through.

“I see your response is as quick as always. How is Komomo...?”

“Happy and healthy in mind and body. She’s been devoting herself to training day and night because of her embarrassment.”

“I see. Miss Aoi has done well.”

Hayate sighed in relief to hear that his little sister Komomo was healthy. While they may have let someone make the first move, the Saga family’s bodyguards were excellent, reliable, and trustworthy.

For the record, Aoi was Komomo’s personal attendant, and the person in charge of protecting her and her surroundings. Because Aoi accompanied Komomo absolutely everywhere, Hayate assumed the one that saved Komomo had been Aoi.

“Actually, an unknown boy was the one that saved Komomo and apprehended the perpetrator. One with splendid skills, at that.” Gouki corrected Hayate with an expression that conveyed he was at a complete loss.

“Oh? What a wonderful person he must be. I would love to pay him a visit and express my gratitude. Where might I find him?” Impressed, Hayate inquired after his whereabouts without thinking.

“As I said, it was an unknown boy. One who disappeared immediately, that is. We have no idea who or what he is.” Gouki sighed listlessly and shook his head.

“That... is a problem.”

“Indeed — it’s a problem. We can’t even thank him. Well... That’s all I have to inform you of for now. Has anything changed on your side?”

“No, there have been no signs of anyone targeting me as of yet...”

“I see.”

Hayate placed a hand against his mouth in thought, then recalled the letter tucked into his chest pocket and took it out. “...Oh, but there is something. This is unrelated to Komomo, but Lady Yuba entrusted me with a letter for you, father.”

“Oh? From Lady Yuba, you say. Let me have a look.”

Gouki accepted the letter from Hayate and opened it with a refined gesture that was unsuiting of his stern physique. He then unrolled the scroll, shifted his center of gravity, and stared intently at the letter.

It’s hard to believe there is anyone so foolish as to wrong this family with my father as the head...

As Gouki read the letter, Hayate contemplated over Komomo’s kidnapping attempt.

Gouki was a renowned military figure, said to be the strongest in the Kingdom of Karasuki and feared for his second name, the Fierce God Gouki. There were tales of how he once caused ten thousand enemies to tremble in the war with the neighboring Kingdom of Rokuren.

He was generally strict with his family, too, especially during Hayate’s training, which was a time when he truly acted like a demon. However, he was much softer in front of his daughter, Komomo.

As Hayate was lost in such thoughts, Gouki muttered his name.

“...Hayate.”

His voice was wavering slightly. No, not just his voice — the hands that clutched the letter, and his boulder-like body, were both faintly trembling.

He had evidently been shaken by something.

“Y-Yes. What is it?” Hayate asked in a high-pitched voice, his eyes widening in surprise.

“And so, you met Sir R-... I mean, a boy named Rio?” Gouki asked about Rio for some reason.

“Yes. We interacted during my stay at Lady Yuba’s residence...”

“What kind of boy was he?”

“...He had a good-natured personality. Gentle and polite, he was a very serious boy. He seemed to be a practitioner of martial arts, as his skills showed. He was most certainly a person of interest. I almost wanted to invite him to our family, if he was not serving anyone else. I believe you would have liked him, too, father.” Despite finding the question strange, Hayate spoke about his impression of Rio honestly.

“Fool. You’ve no idea...” Gouki muttered with a huff, but it was too quiet to reach Hayate’s ears.

“Yes?” Hayate tilted his head.

Gouki chuckled to himself with a grin and stood up straight. “I will be taking Kayoko out of the house for a while. You wait on the estate with Komomo.”

With that, Gouki walked out of the room.

“...What was that about?” Hayate muttered in a daze to no one in particular, now alone in the room.

Rio stared back at the two of them in a daze. They left a much more friendly impression than he had been expecting, having been imagining what kind of people they were up until that moment.

“...It is an honor to meet you, Your Majesty, King Homura, and Your Highness, Queen Shizuku. My name is Rio. I am extremely delighted to be granted an audience with your countenance on this occasion,” Rio introduced himself courteously after they stared at each other for a few seconds. Then, Homura gave a strained laugh.

“I am simply meeting my adorable grandchild. There is no need for that manner of etiquette and speech, and no need to be so uptight.”

“That is correct. You are our grandson.”

The royal couple spoke with a hint of mellow reservation.

“With your pardon, then... I’ll do my best.” Rio nodded awkwardly.

“It looks like we’ll need to deepen our familial relations first. We both seem to be bewildered. Let us exchange words regarding that first, shall we?”

“Yes, there’s so much that I wish to tell you, and so much that I’d like to ask. Although our time is limited, let us chat to our hearts content.”

Homura’s lips curled up at the mouth as Shizuku smiled elegantly. “Now, shall we sit down first?”

“Yes, excuse me.” Rio took a seat.

“Oh, Rio. I’m so glad to meet you. You really are identical to Ayame,” Shizuku said in a clearly animated way. Her gaze was fixed on Rio’s face as she took in all his features and the aura that were similar to Ayame’s.

“I personally feel that you are identical to my mother...” Rio confessed shyly.

“Oh, really?” Shizuku tilted her head curiously.

“Yes. If my mother was here right now, I’d mistake you for her sister.”

“Oh? Oh my. Dear me, how embarrassing... Even though I’m already a grandma.” Shizuku’s cheeks reddened in embarrassment.

Though she was being humble, her appearance was truly youthful. As Ayame’s mother, she should have been upper-middle age, yet she could pass off as someone at the prime of their life.

After that, they fumbled their way through a conversation together, closing the distance between them. Shizuku’s range of expressions was vibrant, and she easily burst into laughter at Rio’s stories.

Then, after they had talked for several minutes...

“Shizuku... I feel like it’s been a while since I’ve seen you laugh in such a carefree way,” Homura said, seeing the elegant smile blooming on Shizuku’s face.

“Oh my, don’t say that. That would mean I’ve been smiling in a fake way this entire time,” Shizuku said with a cute pout.

“Oh no, my dear. Forgive me — that was not my intention,” Homura apologized in a hurry.

At that, Shizuku smiled happily. “You seem to be having more fun than usual too, King Homura,” she said.

“That... is probably because Rio is here.”

“Yes, indeed.”

Homura and Shizuku shared a smile with each other, then nonchalantly exchanged a look with a small nod.

“Hey, Rio. Would you like to tell us about Ayame and Zen?” Shizuku suddenly asked.

They had been talking in order to deepen their relationship until now, but the intention of this question was clearly different. Homura and Shizuku wanted to know about the aftermath of what had happened to the two they chased out of their kingdom. It wasn’t simply a question asked out of curiosity.

“...To begin with the conclusion, both of them have passed away already,” Rio said in a slightly subdued tone.

“...We have been informed of that already. However...”

“We’d like to know more, like the reason why they died, or how they lived.” Shizuku hesitated to say her words, so Homura voiced her question out loud resolutely. Their eyes were locked onto Rio’s with certainty.

“...My father passed away while I was too young to remember anything, so I’m afraid I only have memories of my time with my mother. If that is all right with you...”

“Is that so... Then, could you tell us about what about your life that you remember?”

“...I understand.”

Rio took a deep breath and nodded slowly. Then, he began to speak about his father’s death in the way that it had been conveyed to him by his mother, as well as his memories with Ayame. The details were mostly similar to what he had told Yuba before — that Zen was working as an adventurer who one day messed up on the job and died, leaving Rio and Ayame to live alone until Rio turned five years old.

“My mother was a kind person who was always smiling. That’s why I thought it was natural for it just to be the two of us when I was a child. She had never once shown me any sadness over my father’s death,” Rio said with regard to Ayame’s personality.

“We were, by no means, wealthy in the least. But while he was alive, my father had earned a lot of money for us, so we were able to get by without a need for my mother to work. Our neighbors would look at us with prejudice just for having different colored hair, but those days were filled with happiness. However, my life with my mother didn’t last for very long. When I was five years old, my mother... She passed away.” Unable to determine how far he should talk, Rio hesitated to continue.

“When you were five... How did you live from that point onward, then?” Shizuku asked fearfully.

Rio had braced himself in case they inquired after the reason of his mother’s death, so he relaxed in relief. Apparently the fact he had lost both his parents by the age of five had a much stronger impact.

“...I became an orphan in the poorer part of town.” Rio said casually, with a hint of a bitter smile mixed in.

“Oh...” Shizuku looked like she would start crying at any moment. Homura had his eyes closed as he clenched his fists tightly.

“But I was only an orphan until the age of seven.” Rio said with a small shrug.

“Is that so... How did you live after the age of seven?” Homura asked.

“I saved an important person of the kingdom by chance, and was granted enrollment into an education institute managed by the kingdom as a reward.”

“Oh? An educational institute... We have such institutions in this kingdom too, but only court nobles and certain military families are permitted entry. Was it different in that kingdom?”

“No, there was no difference. Everyone around me was what you would call a court noble or royalty in this kingdom.”

“...Then you must have suffered greatly.” Homura immediately guessed that Rio had been subjected to much discrimination based on his social status.

“No, it is true that the hostility toward me was high, but there was someone there who treated me kindly, too. Thanks to them, I can proudly say my days there were fun,” Rio said with a gentle smile. It was all thanks to Celia.

But that wasn’t enough to appease Homura and Shizuku’s emotions, as they continued to avoid eye contact with him. Gouki and Kayoko, who had been listening silently from the side, also had expressions of pain on their faces.

“From there, I attended the academy until I was twelve years old, before departing for this land.”

“I had heard there were kingdoms far to the west, but... you did well making it here unharmed. Thanks to that, we were able to meet you.” Homura lowered his head deeply in an excessive show of gratitude toward Rio. Knowing that the king wasn’t in a position where he should be easily lowering his head to others, Homura’s gratitude resounded greatly within Rio.

“When I was young, my mother would tell me a lot about you. And she promised me that she would someday take me to this land. She wasn’t able to fulfill that promise, but I have always wanted to travel here. At the very least, I wanted to make a grave for them in their home town.”

“Ayame promised such a thing to you...” Homura bit down on his lip. He was filled with a mixture of happiness, regret, and shame.

The sound of Shizuku’s sobbing cries echoed through the room as Homura closed his eyes and fell silent. The silence continued for a while.

Then, after some time, Homura took a deep breath and inquired after the one thing that Rio wanted to be asked the least. “...Rio. Would you tell us how Ayame died?”

“...I must warn you, it may be difficult to hear. Do you still wish to know anyway?” Rio asked, questioning the amount of resolution behind Homura and the others. The story would most certainly be sickening to hear.

“We must know what happened... What happened in her last moments. And, if need be...”

We will blame ourselves — Homura’s face darkened with that implication.

“I’m sorry... I know it must be cruel to ask you to speak the truth, but we simply cannot bear remaining in the dark,” Shizuku agreed, not lifting her head.

The two of them spoke in a calm tone filled with their strong determination and will.

“Is that so...” Rio closed his eyes as though waffling over something, before he took a deep breath.

“My mother... was killed. Right before my eyes,” he said bluntly.

“...” While they expected it to some extent, Homura and the others were still visibly shocked.

“The person who killed my mother was a man named Lucius.”

Rio paid them no mind as he started to recall what had happened at the time. That was what they had wished for, after all.

For the five years after Zen’s death, Ayame rented a modest house in the capital of the kingdom of Beltrum and had raised Rio there. Fortunately, there was enough money saved to allow her to raise Rio alone as long as they didn’t spend extravagantly. However, the burden on her was greater than expected, and she couldn’t even afford to take her eyes away from Rio for just a moment to do a little shopping. During times like that, an adventurer named Lucius would help out Ayame. Ayame was acquaintances with Lucius back from when Zen was still alive.

Back then, Ayame had retired from adventuring when she became pregnant with Rio. Zen had continued in the adventuring industry alone for a while, but ever since one day in particular, he had started to complete missions together with Lucius.

Zen had the skills, but he was still a foreigner in a strange land. Lucius had called out to him while he was still getting used to the kingdom, and looked after him in various ways. Because of that, Zen brought Lucius home and introduced him to Ayame. That was how Ayame first came into contact with him.

Then, when Zen died shortly after Rio was born, Lucius supported Ayame in myriad ways as she devoted herself to raising her child. For instance, he went shopping on Ayame’s behalf, visited with gifts in tow, or played with the young Rio.

At the time, neither Ayame nor Rio doubted that Lucius was a friendly and kind person; since he was an adventurer, his eyes were sharp, and there was some form of intensity behind him. However, his facial features were refined, and his personality was considerate and sociable, like a gentleman’s.

It had all been an act.

One day, while Ayame had gone out on an errand in the neighborhood, she told Rio: “I’ll be back soon, so don’t leave the house if someone you don’t know comes.” Then, she had left her five-year-old son at home alone.

Immediately after Ayame left, Lucius visited the house. Rio had followed Ayame’s words at first and pretended like no one was home.

“Rio — you’re there, aren’t you? It’s me, Lucius. I met Ayame out there and she told me to come look after you. Could you open the door for me?” a voice said from the other side of the door. Once he realized it was Lucius, Rio immediately opened the door. Rio knew Lucius very well, so he trusted him fully.

However, Lucius had done a complete 180 into a cruel and cold-hearted person.

“Gah...” Lucius walked into the house and kicked Rio in the abdomen.

The sudden impact to his stomach sent Rio’s small body flying; he had seen a glimpse of Lucius’ foot making contact with his stomach, but he couldn’t understand why Lucius would do such a thing.

“Wh...y...?” Rio rolled on the floor, wheezing.

“Hahaha. Listen up, Rio. In this world, sometimes there are wolves in sheep’s clothing. They love to betray people’s trust and spread malice. Demons like me love that more than anything. They’d even pretend to be good people to do it. That’s why you shouldn’t trust people so easily, you know?”

Lucius grabbed Rio’s head and peered at his face. “Now you’ve grown one wiser,” he added, and curled his lips in a joyful grin. A glint of madness could be seen in his eyes.

“Do you know what a demon’s favorite thing is, Rio?”

“...” Rio watched with fearful eyes, his head still clutched in Lucius’ grip.

“Demons... When they see things people find precious or beautiful, they want to break them and ruin them to the point of no return. The face of a human betrayed by someone they greatly trusted is especially delicious.” Lucius chatted away talkatively, but Rio couldn’t understand his words at all.

“But... You know, at your young age, you wouldn’t get what I’m saying anyway, would you? That’s why it isn’t as rewarding destroying brats like you, and I don’t really like it,” he said with a sigh.

“I can really spice things up with you, though. With Ayame — who treasures you more than anything — as the main dish.”

Again, Rio was unable to understand anything that Lucius was saying. All he knew was that he was afraid of the man. But it wasn’t just fear — faint buds of hatred were also trying to bloom within his chest. It caused Rio to glare at Lucius with an indescribable feeling.

“...Oh? So you can make a good expression, too.” Lucius’ eyes widened with interest as he chuckled with a grin. He kicked Rio’s prone form and rolled him face-up, before stepping on his stomach and pressing him into the floor.

“Guh...” A cry of pain left Rio’s mouth.

“Well, having you wailing and crying would just be a killjoy. Let’s silence you before Ayame gets home, shall we? Don’t worry, it won’t hurt. It’s just a little drug... One that paralyzes your body and makes your mind gradually grow hazy. If Ayame gets home early, you may even be awake to see her for the last act.”

Lucius grabbed Rio by the hair and lifted his face, then reached into his pocket and took out a small metal bottle that he thrust into Rio’s mouth. Unable to spit it out, Rio swallowed the unknown substance. Immediately after that, a burning heat seared within his stomach, and gnawed away at his body bit by bit. His breathing grew shallow, and he couldn’t find strength in his limbs.

That was when the door opened. It swung open a little faster than usual, most likely because of how it was unlocked.

It was Ayame.

“Welcome home, Ayame! You’re early,” Lucius called out to her casually, with Rio still underfoot. Rio was panting in pain, face flushed with a fever.

“W-What are you doing, Lucius?!” Ayame froze where she stood in a daze, managing to speak in a high-pitched voice once she processed the situation.

“Haha. Isn’t it obvious...?” Lucius smiled in delight as he spoke to Ayame.

At this point, Rio’s consciousness had already faded, and he couldn’t make out the words they exchanged. A fog had fallen over his vision, but he still had some vague sense of awareness left. He remained in that state for so long, it felt like it would never end. The only thing that was carved vividly into his memory was the hazy sight of Lucius abusing Ayame.

At the very end, however, Rio had the vague feeling Ayame had hugged him. While he couldn’t be certain whether it was a dream or reality, Ayame had smiled at him gently with tears in her eyes.

It had most likely been real. That’s what he wanted to believe.

But, behind Ayame, Lucius was standing with his sword in hand. He made eye contact with Rio and curled his lips in a repulsive grin.

That was the last thing Rio remembered. When he awakened, Rio had been thrown into a back alleyway of the capital. His clothes were stained with someone’s blood splatter, but Rio refused to accept reality and wandered around the capital in a daze, searching for his house. He had no idea how long he walked for, but Rio eventually found the plain old house they had been renting. However, the door to the house had been locked shut.

Rio found a neighbor he recognized somewhat and asked them for his mother’s whereabouts, the neighbor was disgusted by him, and told him that she was dead. The house was a vacant house, now.

After that, Rio lived on the streets of the slums for the two years until he enrolled into the Royal Academy, all while carrying a hatred toward Lucius in his chest the entire time.

“...And that’s what happened,” Rio declared with a frown.

With that, he had revealed his entire dark past — one that he had never told anyone else before. Everyone in the room — Homura, Shizuku, Gouki, and Kayoko — was trembling. The budding emotions in their chests may have been anger, or sorrow, or perhaps something else. Rio stared back at Homura and the others with a little bit of regret, wondering if he really should have told them the truth.

“Rio, you must bear so much resentment toward us, for causing Ayame to suffer such a thing...” Homura murmured softly in a voice that suppressed his emotions.

“I do resent you—” Rio said bluntly, without a hint of hesitation.

“...” Homura and the others shook greatly. They had been prepared to be cursed, but Rio’s frank words stabbed them deep in their hearts.

“—is what someone else might say if they had been in the same situation as me. However, I do not feel any particular resentment toward you,” Rio added with a bitter smile.

Homura and the others stared at Rio with dumbfounded expressions.

“I’m sorry. I didn’t mean to surprise you like that. But... everyone is greatly misunderstanding something, here. Please don’t feel any misplaced guilt, or think of yourselves as the wrong-doers.”

“...Why do you say that?” Homura asked in a hoarse voice.

“I was raised lovingly by my mother, and watched her from the closest perspective possible. That’s why I know: my mother did not hate you. If anything, I believe she felt grateful for being able to marry my father. That’s why it wouldn’t be right for me to hate you,” Rio said, his features breaking down at the memories he recalled of his mother.

“Is that, so...” Homura and the others trembled once more, hanging their heads low. They couldn’t bear the feelings of remorse and embarrassment.

Misplaced guilt, thinking of themselves as the wrong-doers... Rio’s words were right on the mark. What Rio had said just now stabbed them deeper in the heart than when he had said he resented them. They realized exactly how helpless they were.

“But, Rio. Allow me to ask one thing: what do you think of this Lucius, the man who killed Ayame? Can you forgive him?”

“No. I can’t forgive him, most likely, ever. Just recently, I realized there were things in this world that are absolutely unforgivable.” Rio shook his head as he suppressed his emotions.

“Then, do you seek revenge?”

“I’m not considering living only for the sake of revenge, since I don’t know where he is, or if he’s even alive. However, if I do meet that man someday, then with these hands I will...”

“...I see. I am a king, after all; I have seen countless repulsive humans up until this point. That is why I can understand the emotions that you carry, and will not deny them. But, if you are to pursue the road to vengeance, there is one thing I must tell you first,” Homura said, narrowing his eyes as though to see through Rio’s determination.

“What is it?” Rio took on Homura’s gaze head-on.

“Vengeance is not justice. The dead may not wish for revenge, and vengeance will only give birth to new vengeance. Consequently, the road to vengeance only leads to hell. Even if you want to turn back, you won’t be able to. You understand that, right?”

“Yes, I am aware.”

“You can still turn back right now. Will you still kill him, knowing that?”

“...Yes, that is what I have decided. I will no longer avert my eyes from reality. From people’s malice, from my own weaknesses. That is why I am willing to dirty these hands if necessary.” Rio asserted his own will plainly, with a determined expression.

Homura looked into Rio’s eyes carefully; his caramel-colored eyes showed no signs of delusion or madness. They were the eyes of someone who knew that there was no such thing as absolute morals in this world, yet had chosen to stick by their own morals anyway. That was why he wasn’t about to resort to any means possible for his vengeance, and he wouldn’t incur anyone else’s enmity for his own selfish reason.

Homura sighed with resignation.

“...Is that so. In that case, I will not stop you from seeking vengeance.”

If Rio had lost sight of his way, Homura would have imparted words, as his grandfather, to lead him back to a less painful road. However, there was no point in doing that to Rio as he was right now. From his experience as a king that had lived a long life, Homura could understand that human emotions weren’t so fragile that they could be washed away with a few idealistic words.

“...However, as your grandfather, I wish to know whether you have the strength to carry out that will of yours. Would you consider facing off with Gouki?”

“...You wish for me to spar with Lord Gouki?” Rio’s eyes widened, and he tilted his head at Homura’s sudden proposal.

“Forgive me — I have bewildered you with my sudden insolence. It is simply the meddlesome actions of the elderly...”

“No, I just haven’t completely grasped the point of such an action...”

“It’s about Lucius. From what you told us just now, he sounds quite skilled. With a personality as repulsive as his, I wouldn’t doubt that Zen’s death could also be attributed to him. Wouldn’t you agree?”

“...Yes. I have considered it as a possibility.”

“That being said, I knew Zen very well. At the very least, he wasn’t the type you could easily gain the upper hand on in a fight. Isn’t that right, Gouki?” Homura said, looking at him.

Gouki nodded silently, before offering his own opinion on the matter. “Yes, most sneak attacks wouldn’t be able to phase a man like him. If that foul man truly took out Zen with his own hands, then reluctant as I am to admit it, I believe he must be quite powerful.”

“That’s how it is. You must be at least Zen’s strength or greater if you ever wish to confront Lucius. And, even if he didn’t kill Zen, strength is invaluable for a journey like yours, is it not?” Homura asked.

“Yes,” Rio said, nodding.

“In that regard, Gouki was once evenly matched with Zen, and now has many years of military experience under his belt. He is a veteran warrior unmatched not only in this kingdom, but the neighboring kingdoms as well. There is no one in this kingdom stronger than this man that could test your true abilities. How about it — would you like to spar with him?”

In other words, Homura wanted to train Rio.

On the battlefield, he held the nickname of the “Fierce God Gouki” — the number of strong opponents he had slayed was immeasurable. Under Gouki, his grandchild would be able to gain valuable experience, Homura thought. Behind his words was a glimpse into the utmost faith he had in Gouki.

“I wouldn’t dare to dream of such a thing. If he would be so kind as to teach me, then I gladly accept.” Rio nodded with a bold smile.

“Is that so? Then may I leave Rio to you, Gouki?” Homura asked of him.

“Of course. Accepting this duty would be my honor.” Gouki nodded with plenty of emotion behind the action.

“Then, I shall leave it to you. ...Now, Rio. Forgive me, but I have come here today using the time between my official duties. We will have to wrap things up for now. Please, make yourself at home under the care of Gouki’s residence. Don’t forget to spar with him.”

Considering Ayame’s past, Rio’s identity wasn’t to be revealed under any circumstances, so no one was to know of this secret meeting. If the meeting had continued for too long, the unused time in their schedules might be questioned by the retainers, so they had reached their time limit.

Thus, the meeting moved to wrap itself up for the day.

“Rio, could you come here for a moment?” Shizuku stood up and suddenly called out to him. “...Yes, of course.” Rio nodded, hesitantly approaching Shizuku. She gently hugged him.

“You grew up so wonderfully, all by yourself. Well done making it this far. Thank you so much.” Burying her face in Rio’s larger body, Shizuku was moved to tears.

Rio had stiffened faintly at suddenly being hugged out of the blue, but he soon melted under Shizuku’s warmth. It somehow reminded him of Ayame.

“No... I’m the one who is happy to be able to meet the two of you.” Rio timidly hugged Shizuku back.

“Yes...” With a fleeting smile, Shizuku looked up at Rio’s face from up close.

The expression Rio could see on Shizuku’s face from a distance wasn’t one of royalty, but a loving grandmother instead, though her outward appearance was slightly young for a grandmother. Homura gazed at the two of them with an expression filled with familial love.

“Now, let us go, Shizuku.”

“All right...” At Homura’s prompt, Shizuku reluctantly left the room.

“If you’d please, Sir Rio — Allow me to lead the way.” Once the king and queen had exited, Gouki spoke up quietly.

“Yes, please do.”

◇◇◇

After the meeting, Rio left the royal castle and moved to the Saga estate.

The Saga family residence was located in a military town close to the heart of the capital, where the streets were quiet and a serene atmosphere hung in the air. Every residence in the area was enclosed within walls, but there wasn’t much greenery for shelter, so the sturdy but wonderful mansions were neatly lined.

“It’s this way.”

As for the Saga residence, even amongst the other military town buildings, the mansion was particularly splendid. The materials used were wood and mortar, with some sections painted a crimson red. Rio passed through the gate of the estate as he admired its appearance. When the two guiding him entered the garden, the voice of a young girl echoed.

“Father! Mother! Welcome home!”

A cute little girl around ten years of age appeared. She wore a martial arts uniform and hakama, with a single wooden sword clutched in her hand. Her eyes were like beautiful gemstones, her facial features were defined, and her white skin was smooth like porcelain. Each feature was of the finest quality, making her the picture of innocence. Furthermore, her jet-black, silk-like hair reached down her back, rubbing against her clothes to play a beautiful tune.

...Hm?

Rio froze midstep when he saw the girl. He felt like he had seen the girl somewhere before... And very recently, at that.

A woman appeared behind the girl.

“My Lord, My Lady... Welcome home. Is that person to be a gues—” The woman gave a respectful greeting when she saw Rio’s face and stiffened on the spot.

When Rio saw the woman’s face, his sense of deja vu suddenly made sense. The two that had appeared were the people he had encountered walking through the capital just the other day: the girl who had almost been kidnapped, and her bodyguard. He was taken aback by the completely unexpected twist of fate to see them here.

“How disrespectful, Aoi!” Gouki scolded the woman who had froze at the sight of Rio.

“P-Please forgive me!” Aoi paled and quickly bowed her head.

“...My Lord, there must be some kind of reason for this. Aoi, speak your mind.” Kayoko sought an explanation from her, quickly picking up on the reactions that Rio and Aoi had. She suspected that they had possibly been previously acquainted.

“U-Umm, that person there is the one who saved Lady Komomo,” Aoi disclosed the reason nervously.

“Saved me?” Komomo, the aforementioned girl, tilted her head curiously. That being said, it was understandable that she couldn’t recall anything, since she had been unconscious for the duration of the kidnapping incident.

“The other day, I ran into that girl over there being attacked by some ruffians...” Rio confessed somewhat guiltily.

“O-Ooh?! Is that so! What a tremendous coincidence!” Gouki’s eyes widened when he understood.

“At the time, I chose to make an exit before things became too troublesome, so it’s only natural for her to be surprised. Please, don’t scold her,” Rio said to help out Aoi.

“H-Hmm. If that’s how it is, then... we are thankful beyond measure, and are forever in your debt. Aoi, offer your gratitude, too.” Gouki glared at Aoi, who lowered her head at Rio.

“I-I’m so very sorry for the rudeness I showed earlier! I’d like to offer my utmost gratitude for your generous consideration. Thank you very much!” Aoi expressed her apologies and gratitude with a near-excessive amount of courtesy. Judging by the way Gouki interacted with Rio, she had guessed he was a fairly high-ranking person that was to be respected.

“N-No, it’s fine... I didn’t do anything special, after all.” Rio shook his head with a strained smile.

For some reason, he always felt extremely uncomfortable when people treated him with an excessive amount of respect. He slumped his shoulders a little, resigning himself to being worn out by this type of treatment during his stay.

“Umm... If I may?” Komomo approached Rio timidly.

“Hm? What is it?”

“It’s nice to meet you. My name is Saga Komomo — thank you very much for saving me from those ruffians the other day,” Komomo said politely, bowing her head at Rio.

“Thank you for the courtesy. My name is Rio. Were you hurt at all from that?” Rio replied with a faint smile.

“No. Thanks to you, I’m the picture perfect of health!” Komomo laughed innocently with a fist pump.

“That’s great to hear.”

“Lord... Rio, thank you very much for saving my daughter. I would like to thank you from the bottom of my heart as well.”

The brief pause after the “Lord” title was probably due to the resistance Gouki had within himself. They had decided on the way here that Rio would be treated as a regular guest during his stay in the mansion, but putting that into practice was easier said than done. Gouki and Kayoko’s attitude toward Rio thus far had been more like that of a most valued guest, rather than a regular guest.

“It was nothing. You have a very cute daughter.”

“I am honored by the compliment. ...If I may ask, Lord Rio. What would you like to do about the sparring match? Preparations can be made right away, if you so wish.” Gouki happily thanked Rio, before he moved to gauge Rio’s interest in the match.

“That’s right. Then... May I ask you to make the preparations now?” Rio nodded with a huff of laughter. He was also quite eager for the fight.

While he had had no lack of sparring partners during his time in the spirit folk village, he had mostly trained by himself since coming to the Yagumo region, so he was quite hungry for a mock battle with someone that was actually powerful.

“Father, will you be having a contest?!” Komomo’s expression brightened dramatically at the mention of a sparring match.

“Indeed, a contest it is. Is Hayate in the training grounds?”

“Yes! I was training there myself just a few moments ago.”

“I see. Then, you may come along and observe too. There will certainly be something to gain today. Now, Lord Rio — please follow me. This is the way to the training grounds.”

Thus, Rio, Gouki, Kayoko, Komomo, and Aoi all made their way to the training grounds.

The party arrived at the grounds to the sight of Hayate silently swinging his wooden sword. The training grounds were outdoors, boasting a rather wide area of land. At the corner of the area was a dojo-like building.

Hayate spotted Gouki and Kayoko and beamed brightly. “Ooh. Father, mother, welcome ho— Wait, Lord Rio?!” When he noticed Rio behind them, he let out a much more frantic voice.

“Good day, Lord Hayate. I’d say long time no see, but it hasn’t been that long.” Rio greeted him in lieu of their reunion, smiling wryly at his reaction.

“I-Indeed. But why are you here, Lord Rio?”

“Lord Rio will be staying at our house as a guest. We will now have a sparring match together, so you should observe, too. Prepare the wooden swords.” Gouki dismissed Hayate’s bewilderment with a detached explanation.

“Y-Yes, sir!” Hayate agreed in a panic and went to fetch the wooden swords for use in a mock battle. After that, the rest of the preparations were completed in the blink of an eye, and Rio and Gouki each took a wooden sword in hand as they faced each other at the center of the training grounds.

Kayoko, who would act as the referee, approached the two of them.

“In our kingdom, it is custom before a sparring match for warriors to determine the level of danger, from that of a real combat situation, to something less so. What kind of agreement would you like to spar under?” she asked.

“Lord Gouki, what would you like to do?” Rio inquired.

“I shall leave it to you, Lord Rio.” Gouki yielded the decision to Rio.

“In that case, I would like a sparring match that conforms to real combat.” Rio requested without hesitation.

In response, Gouki lips curled into a smile he couldn’t hold back. Kayoko’s expression also twitched with a faint smile.

Meanwhile, Hayate had a strangely troubled look on his face, while Komomo was gazing at Rio with admiration in her eyes. In Aoi’s case, she was watching Rio with anxiety and concern.

They each had a visibly different expression.

“...I understand. Then to put it bluntly, anything short of killing is allowed. We can heal a decent amount of injuries with spirit arts, so please don’t hold yourself back. Is that all right?” Kayoko looked at Rio to check.

“I have no objections,” Rio assented with no sign of fear.

“Then, both parties — distance yourselves and take your stances.”

At Kayoko’s orders, Rio and Gouki walked an appropriate distance away, opposite each other. They familiarized themselves with the grip of the wooden swords and assumed their stances.

“Begin!”

Kayoko signaled the start of the sparring match.

Immediately after, Rio moved forward as though he had teleported through space, closing the distance between him and Gouki in an instant and swinging his sword.

“?!”

Gouki was astonished by how Rio suddenly appeared before his eyes, but jumped forward without hesitation. He figured that if he tried to carelessly retreat, it would only make him fall more behind at the start of their sparring match. In an all or nothing move, he lowered his defensive stance and ran forward, evading Rio’s sword as he tried to slip into range of his opponent’s chest.

Rio dropped to his knees at once and aimed a knee strike at Gouki’s stooped stance. However, once he realized the pommel of Gouki’s sword was being aimed at his knees, Rio immediately retreated.

Both parties distanced themselves and regrouped, adjusting their stances as they examined each other.

Hmm... I was practically unable to predict his movements. Perhaps it is due to the fact that he had to grow up so quickly, but he has amazing skill for such a young age. A cold sweat ran down Gouki’s spine as his mouth curved in a daring smile.

Normally, for a human to move their body, they needed to put strength into their physique and allow for the accumulation of excess movements. However, when it came to experienced martial artists, they had the eyes to see through excess like that and take the upper hand. They also had the acquired technique to relax their own actions so as to not be seen through by their opponent.

Through the short exchange just now, Gouki had ascertained that Rio was an experienced fighter.

At that speed, I mustn’t let the distance between us widen tactlessly. Maintaining distance will only lead to me falling behind... And the moment I lose focus is the moment I will be hunted down...

With that in mind, Gouki approached Rio as close as he could get. He figured that at this short distance, Rio wouldn’t be able to use his superhuman speed out of avoidance of a collision... and he wasn’t wrong.

In the spirit folk village, Rio had learned during his studies of spirit arts to forcefully accelerate his body using wind spirit arts with no excess movements, as well as the ability to combine that with techniques to relax his movements and catch his opponent off guard. However, the drawback of this movement technique of his was that the acceleration was too fast and didn’t allow for maneuverability, meaning its use was limited when his opponent got too close. Because of that, he could only show his true power when fighting in wide fields where he could move freely.

He’s closing the distance between us... I suppose that’s to be expected of one so experienced in battle. He’d probably crush me the moment I try to fall back and widen the distance again. If that’s the case...

Rio admired how Gouki immediately counteracted his speed — as expected of the one they call the Fierce God, he thought. But in that next moment, he relaxed his strength and stepped into Gouki’s space. Gouki immediately reacted by swinging his sword, but Rio easily stopped the blow. Their respective wooden swords came into contact with ferocity, causing a shrill noise to echo throughout the training grounds.

The two were suddenly right in each other’s space, exchanging blows too fast for the eye to follow. They were both attacking while concealing any signs of attack, and both seeing through the other. After the intense exchange of offensive and defensive moves continued for several moments, the two sword tips struck the ground as though crossing over.

“How fearsome. To think you’d have such skills at such a young age... You have truly surpassed both Zen and I from back then. And, you have yet to reach your golden age in terms of both body and experience too...” Gouki stopped moving and grinned.

“The only thing I never stopped doing was training.”

“I’m beat...” Gouki said as he swung his wooden sword at Rio once more. However, Rio turned his body and cut into Gouki’s side, evading his slash as he let out his own attack. Gouki pulled his thrusted-out sword in immediately, stopping Rio’s blow. Their swords collided fiercely once again as the two of them pushed back at each other in their close-fought match.

“...It sure doesn’t look that way.”

“Fights that make my heart dance like this don’t happen too often. Having the opponent be Lord Rio on top of that makes it all the more invigorating.”

As he spoke, Gouki languidly withdrew his body and immediately stepped forward with force, releasing three consecutive strikes faster than one could visibly detect.

And yet, Rio handled those strikes deftly.

Gouki had swung his sword for years — no, decades. His thrusts just now were packed with the fruits of his labor and abilities, which was why Rio thought that Gouki was unmistakably the strongest of all those he had fought up until now. As a human, his physical abilities might have been inferior to werebeasts and dwarves even when enhanced by spirit arts, but his battle techniques far surpassed them.

“Zen was a man with an innate talent for the arts of battle, but I see that talent has been inherited by you quite thoroughly. No, you may even have more than he did,” Gouki said, launching a two-thrust strike that was even sharper than the earlier three consecutive strikes.

Rio aimed for the timing of when the second thrust was fully extended to repel Gouki’s sword, making Gouki lose his balance a bit. Rio used that chance to attack, aiming a roundhouse kick to his torso. Gouki tried to immediately guard himself with his left arm, but his entire body was sent flying.

Kuh, using both swordcraft and martial arts together... Splendid. The damage Gouki received was by no means light, but his expression was cheerful.

Hayate and Aoi watched the sight of Gouki being blown away in dumbfounded silence. Even the calm Kayoko widened her eyes by a fraction.

Komomo was the only one with sparkling eyes; filled with reverence and adoration, as to not miss a single moment of such a high-order battle unfolding before her.

Gouki used the momentum of being kicked to unthinkingly widen his distance between himself and Rio. However, Rio moved like the wind, and closed in on Gouki in an instant.

With no other choice, Gouki responded to Rio’s challenge. He barely managed to deal with Rio’s consecutive attacks, clearly having gone on defense.

“I can’t believe it... Father...” Hayate was aghast with the thought of Gouki losing.

He couldn’t believe that Gouki, who had been undefeated until now, was seemingly on the losing side. And to a boy younger than himself, no less. Nevertheless, that was what was unfolding before his eyes. Gouki had yet to make a single telling blow against Rio, while Rio had already made several against Gouki.

No... If they had been using real swords instead, Gouki would have already been rendered incapacitated.

Against Gouki’s fighting style, which was focused on his sword, Rio used an ever-changing mix of swordcraft and martial arts as his. On top of making his opponent aware of their sword-focused style, he launched nasty, agonizing attacks without warning.

Gouki was only blocking the fatal blows with his skill and experience, letting a few good attacks land in between. Gouki’s legs were trembling faintly; it was evidence of the accumulated damage. However, he showed no sign of faltering. He endured it through sheer will and fighting spirit, unwilling to let such a wonderful match end so easily.

“Hahaha! How thrilling it is indeed!” Gouki yelled with a brazen smile. Then, he purposefully widened the distance with Rio, whose speed surpassed his own, and smoothly braced his sword without hesitation.

Essence is converging around his sword...

Rio immediately noticed that Gouki was trying to use some kind of skill. He could charge forward and close the distance, but that would be a risky move when he didn’t know what skill his opponent was using.

“F-Father, don’t tell me you’re using that...?!” Hayate yelled from the side of the training grounds. He seemed to have in mind what skill Gouki was about to unleash, as well as the power behind the skill, too.

Rio showed no sign of fear, however. He raised his own essence as though to face the skill Gouki was about to release head on, and watched carefully.

“Hidden Skill, First Blade, Air Slash!”

Gouki swung his sword in a straight line, and a giant horizontal slash in the air came flying toward Rio. It was a wind blade that had been infused with essence through spirit arts.

Unlike magic, spirit arts didn’t require a spell name to be chanted, so it wasn’t actually necessary to give each and every skill a name. However, as spirit arts were miraculous techniques that put one’s own will and imagination into the essence or ode to communicate with mana and bring about different phenomena, the rationality of skill names leading to enhanced will and imagination was real. It was all the more effective when it came to a swordsman as experienced as Gouki, who had found both his ideal stance and the strong spirit to swing his sword in a single decisive stroke through his daily training.

In actuality, the blade of wind he had unleashed was extremely powerful. Against regular humans, it would have been able to tear through and mow down several people at once.

Rio immediately detected the power behind the attack and gave up receiving it with his wooden sword. However, he made no move to evade it, deciding to accept the challenge directly. He manipulated the essence he had drawn from his body and gathered it in his right hand before swinging it like a scythe. Immediately after, a tsunami-like wall of water appeared before Rio’s eyes, crashing into the wind blade.

An explosive sound echoed throughout the training grounds as wind and water scattered about the surroundings.